<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: en | blog.hoatle.info]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/categories/en/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T13:39:58+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[hoatle]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barcamp Hanoi 2009 logo design contest]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/21/barcamp-hanoi-2009-logo-design-contest/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-21T15:06:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/21/barcamp-hanoi-2009-logo-design-contest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/barcamphanoismall2.png" title="Barcamp Hanoi 1 Logo" ></p>

<p>The current logo you’re seeing on top of this page is the logo of Barcamp Hanoi 1. Several months
ago, right after we put it on the homepage,  some people gave us feedback that we should change the
logo. And we see that other Barcamps also change their logo for each individual event. So we think
it’s right time now to announce a tiny logo design contest for Barcamp Hanoi 2009. Then we can use
the winning logo to print banner, T-shirt, official documents and put it on the homepage. You can
read more detail about the contest below:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong>Barcamp Hanoi 2009 Logo Design Contest</strong></p>

<p>Help Barcamp Hanoi create a unique and meaningful logo for the event of 2009.</p>

<p><strong>Reward for the Winner</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Community-Wide recognition for designing the official Barcamp Hanoi 2009 logo featured on the
official homepage.</p></li>
<li><p>A free Barcamp Hanoi 2009 T-Shirt to show off your winning design.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Submission deadline</strong></p>

<p><code>Saturday, February 28th, 11:59 PM (GMT+7)</code></p>

<p><strong>Design Guidelines</strong></p>

<p>The logo should:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Convey the concept of Barcamp (You can use the starting files here)</p></li>
<li><p>Be distinct, unique and easily identifiable (It’s the logo of Barcamp Hanoi, not a general Barcamp)</p></li>
<li><p>Aesthetically fit in with a broad range of site/application designs</p></li>
</ul>


<p>References:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Starting files <a href="http://barcamp.org/SpreadBarCamp">http://barcamp.org/SpreadBarCamp</a></p></li>
<li><p>Sample logos <a href="http://barcamp.org/LogoGallery">http://barcamp.org/LogoGallery</a></p></li>
<li><p>Barcamp Saigon 2008 Logo <a href="http://www.barcampsaigon.org/dokuwiki/doku.php?id=2008_org_logo">http://www.barcampsaigon.org/dokuwiki/doku.php?id=2008_org_logo</a></p></li>
<li><p>Barcamp Logos on Google Image search <a href="http://images.google.com/images?q=Barcamp%20logo&amp;oe=utf-8&amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:unofficial&amp;client=firefox-a&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;sa=N&amp;hl=en&amp;tab=wi">http://images.google.com/images?q=Barcamp%20logo&amp;oe=utf-8&amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:unofficial&amp;client=firefox-a&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;sa=N&amp;hl=en&amp;tab=wi</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>How it works</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>First, create your Logo design. View the Design Guidelines for more details.</p></li>
<li><p>Upload your design to the contest-specific Flickr group <code>Barcamp Hanoi 2009 Logo Design Contest</code>
for review.</p></li>
<li><p>After a week, these designs will be posted online at the homepage of Barcamp Hanoi for public
voting. You determine the <strong>winner</strong>!</p></li>
<li><p>The winning Logo will be used on blog, websites, banners, documents and T-shirt to help promote
Barcamp Hanoi 2009.</p></li>
<li><p>If you have any additional questions, comment right below this post.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong> Submission &amp; Judging Criteria</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>You can submit more than one design.</p></li>
<li><p>Submissions can be made via JPG/GIF/PNG however please be prepared to provide high
resolution/vector graphic versions of your work.</p></li>
<li><p>As part of the submission, participants must be willing to give up all their rights to the
copyright and donate it to the community.</p></li>
<li><p>Tag your photo with the phrase “BCHN 2009 LContest“. This will allow us to search for and pull your
photo into a public image gallery.</p></li>
<li><p>Join the contest-specific Flickr group Barcamp Hanoi 2009 Logo Design Contest and add your image
to the image pool.</p></li>
<li><p>Make sure your Flickr account is linked to an active email address; this is the only means of
contacting the winner!</p></li>
<li><p>Don’t forget, <strong>the submission deadline is Saturday, February 28th, 11:59 PM (GMT+7)</strong>. You have a
week from now to prepare and submit your logo. <strong>Start right now!</strong></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barcamp Hanoi 2 will come soon :)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/20/barcamp-hanoi-2-will-come-soon/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-20T08:11:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/20/barcamp-hanoi-2-will-come-soon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone,</p>

<p>To tell the truth, I&rsquo;m a little envious of some HCM city (Saigon) geeks' activities, especially about Barcamp Saigon 1 and their #H3 :(. What about in Hanoi? Just correct me if I&rsquo;m wrong but it seem there
hasn&rsquo;t been any such interesting events in Hanoi. Here I just want to mention and introduce Barcamp Hanoi 2. You can just google some keyworks orderly to get info: barcamp to have general ideas about what is barcamp, barcampsaigon to know what Saigon geeks did to complete the task of organizing barcamp saigon 1. Then the last keywork is barcamphanoi to know more about Barcamp Hanoi organization status :). And then I will call for organizers + volunteers + participants + some more other things :)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Firstly, about Barcamp Hanoi 2. Why 2? Good question :P, do you know that Barcamp Hanoi 1 was first organized in Vietnam, esp. in Hanoi :). Just check this: <a href="http://blog.exoplatform.org/2007/12/28/barcamp-hanoi/">http://blog.exoplatform.org/2007/12/28/barcamp-hanoi/</a> So, Barcamp Hanoi 1 was organized by eXo employees (esp. by jeremi) just in internal eXo Platform SEA employees. And Now we (Hanoi geeks, bloggers, volunteers&hellip;) are organizing Barcamp Hanoi 2.</p>

<p>After the great success of Barcamp Saigon 1, some efforts to organize Barcamp Hanoi 2
started but in slow progress. Sometime it was supposed to happen before Tet holiday, then just some weeks after Tet holiday. But now we&rsquo;re still preparing for it and the progress is very fast. This post is also
for the purpose of preparation for Barcamp Hanoi 2. Please just check out what is happening in
Barcamp Hanoi 2 organization: <a href="http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en.">http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en.</a>
So here I&rsquo;m calling for organizers for Barcamp Hanoi 2 :). It&rsquo;s open to everyone :). Now the number of organizers can not be counted more than 10 and there are many things to do. Some points just remember: Just join in organizer team when you have passionation + know the spirit of barcamp :). Some volunteers needed for doing other things like food-prepare (don&rsquo;t worry, you do not have to cook any meal :P),
T-shirt design (for designers), sponsorship for persuasive speakers and many other things you can do for Barcamp Hanoi 2.</p>

<p>To participants: Know about barcamp spirit, know about barcamp rules, huh :P. No audience (exept for volunteers), just participants: think about what you will share for Barcamp Hanoi 2 (IT based topic),
and what topics you&rsquo;re interesting. We will have some forms to get info soon. We will make Barcamp Hanoi 2 as great and relaxed as possible. If too many people will go for registering Barcamp Hanoi 2, we will have
to filter out out some people :( because of time + venue + other problems.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Some expectations:</p>

<ul>
<li>What: call it Barcamp Hanoi 2 ;)</li>
<li>When: April 12 (supposed)</li>
<li>Where: RMIT Hanoi or Genetic BK or other?</li>
<li>Who: any one interested in joining barcamp, participants but not audience :)</li>
<li>How many people there: About 200 geeks. So think about some interesting topics to have your seat at Barcamp Hanoi 2. The seats are limited :)</li>
<li>official tag for Barcamp Hanoi 2: barcamphanoi</li>
<li>official website for Barcamp Hanoi 2 will be updated soon, just check it here <a href="http://barcamphanoi.org">http://barcamphanoi.org</a></li>
<li>Twitter to follow: <a href="http://twitter.com/barcamphanoi">http://twitter.com/barcamphanoi</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Links:</p>

<ul>
<li>Google group for organizers: <a href="http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en">http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en</a> (English)</li>
</ul>


<p>Hey, it&rsquo;s time for us to join Barcamp Hanoi 2. What you are waiting for? Spread the world about this event is a resprectedly helpful action.</p>

<p>Just ping some of us here to get more info:</p>

<ol>
<li>Hoat Le (<a href="http://hoatle.net">http://hoatle.net</a>)</li>
</ol>


<p>email: hoatlevan at gmail dot com</p>

<p>yahoo: wild_tiger8607</p>

<p>skype: hoatlevan</p>

<p>twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/hoatle">http://twitter.com/hoatle</a></p>

<p>Thanks for reading :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[my first working day at eXo Platform SEA]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/17/my-first-working-day-at-exo-platform-sea/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-17T02:06:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/17/my-first-working-day-at-exo-platform-sea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is my first working day at eXo Platform SEA, a nice start working day :). Hey, so long no post from my blog sice Tet holiday, now I will blog more often.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;m the lucky one to have chance working at eXo<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> , I&rsquo;ve never thought about it before knowing and meeting Jeremi<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> since Opensocial Hackathon in Hanoi<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>. After the hackathon, Jeremi and I had some discussion, he just introduced me to apply for a position at eXo &ndash; a position where my English learning at HUT and computer learning at HN-Aptech meets, so the best position is document writer. I have some good points of writing English, I will write technical documents for eXo, nice and thank Jeremi so much! Though, this is just the very first step to join eXo. I had English test, interview with 3 guys to check general Java knowledge, openSocial knowledge (Tung) and document writing skill (Cong) and then continue my interview with Brice Revenant<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> &ndash; manager at eXo Platform SEA before our Tet holiday. I had another more test for writing a sample of user guide for comminity management when I was home. Lucky me, everything was nice and today I&rsquo;m very pleased to have my first working day and now blogging about it :).</p>

<p>The unlucky year passed by, last year I lost many things and had so many hardships: I was cheated when helping my friend finding a job, cheated to get address for renting, my motorbike was stolen (I will work hard to buy another by the end of this year), so living in Hanoi is really really dangerous [dangerous in peaceful :))], so I should be more and more and more careful. My bike was stolen at the second term at HUT, too :(. Now the new time for new year: my OpenSocial App took second prize at SE Asia OpenSocial Application contest, however, it is still in developement, hope to release it soon. Got some job offers which is very nice at the time of the world economic meltdown :D. Barcamp Hanoi 2 is being prepared, eXo will be one of the sponsers. I hope that I will have more time to wake everything up, Barcamp Hanoi 2 now seems slow in progress, I&rsquo;m preparing to have a session for Barcamp, too :). Next year will be my next big one after university graduation, more time for work, for meetup :).</p>

<p>Today I had some training to have basic ideas about Portal, how to use and organize it, cool ;). Tomorrow I will have training about WebOS and after that a test will come to check for understanding. Everyone here is nice! I just know some more guys: Tung (eXo Social project leader) and Trong (Portal team leader) from Hackathon, Cong (tester) from the interview, Nga (document writer) and Hang (give me and another guy training) &ndash; today. You can see more staffs here: <a href="http://wiki.exoplatform.org/xwiki/bin/view/Main/Team.">http://wiki.exoplatform.org/xwiki/bin/view/Main/Team.</a></p>

<p>Love this busy and promising year :)</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://exoplatform.com/<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>http://jeremi.info<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/13/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/dir/brice/revenant<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[music-engine Intro]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/16/music-engine-intro/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-16T11:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/16/music-engine-intro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thinking so much about an OpenSocial apps and finally I decided to develop a music-engine application.</p>

<p>What is a music-engine? My music-engine will crawl and index as much as possible any songs in the Internet and reorganize it into datastore in Google Apps.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Music-engine will be the service provider allows me to write OpenSocial apps for any container. Users can search, listen, create and save their own favorite playlists. They can send that playlist to their friends as gifts.</p>

<p>Each user can have his own music-stream life. This is something like Twitter, but this just allows users to recommend any song they like.</p>

<p>These are just some critical features I will try to implement.</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s about copyright issue? Music-engine just crawles and indexes information, it doesn&rsquo;t store any music file on its own server. Every activity such as search, download or any other is from users.</p>

<p>Just some ideas about this. I have completed the database schema and a little about music-engine crawler.</p>

<p>As we know, Google Apps currently supports Python, so it will be coded in Python.</p>

<p>I love PHP, and I have some experience to write a news crawler some months ago. Now I will improve it for music, not news.</p>

<p>If anyone would like to code with me, please contact me. There are many things to do, this is just a project for fun :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSocial Hackathon in Hanoi]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/13/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-13T23:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/13/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is one of the most active day of mine :). With the opensocial hackathon in Hanoi, I have
chance to meet some interesting people.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My morning started in 9 A.M (OMG!!! But it&rsquo;s my normal day; I don&rsquo;t know why but I&rsquo;d really like to
work at late night. Yesterday, I stopped working at about 4 A.M. It&rsquo;s hard to define my work :).
Just do everything with computer: blogging, building some requested websites from customers,
experimenting new technology trend, improve programming skill, oh many more. Just my habit :).</p>

<p>It took me about half an hour to get to eXo Platform office. Coming a bit early (about 10h 20'),
I just saw 2 or 3 geeks sitting there.</p>

<p><strong>Early time</strong></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3208/3127289114_6c42ab2824.jpg?v=0">http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3208/3127289114_6c42ab2824.jpg?v=0</a>" title="Early time" ></p>

<p>11h everyone came. It&rsquo;s just about more than 20 geeks &ndash; this number is less than my expectation ;). I thought there must have been about 50 geeks ;).</p>

<p><strong>Everyone came</strong></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3290/3127289274_56552c8884.jpg?v=0">http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3290/3127289274_56552c8884.jpg?v=0</a>" title="Everyone came" ></p>

<p>I met many geeks from many companies, except me, I&rsquo;m currently not working for any company :), just finding! I don&rsquo;t remember all, but just list some here: eXo Platform (of course, Jereme Joslin, 3 other guys and I have much talk with two of them), Tinh Van Media (<a href="http://xalo.vn;">http://xalo.vn;</a> two 3th-year students from College of Technology), Moore Corporation (<a href="http://nghenhac.info,">http://nghenhac.info,</a> <a href="http://anhso.net">http://anhso.net</a>), VinaLive (<a href="http://phununet.com;">http://phununet.com;</a> 3-4 guys), <a href="http://tamtay.vn">http://tamtay.vn</a> (one guy), guys from <a href="http://teevn.com.">http://teevn.com.</a> Ah, Jason &ndash; now I know him ;), and a guy from <a href="http://newhanoian.xemzi.com/.">http://newhanoian.xemzi.com/.</a> There are more guys but currently I can not remember all.</p>

<p><strong>Where am I? :)</strong></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3196/3127290146_951883aa5b.jpg?v=0">http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3196/3127290146_951883aa5b.jpg?v=0</a>" title="Where am I? :)" ></p>

<p>Jeremi had a very clear presentation about OpenSocial, but I think it&rsquo;s just introduction, everything he said I have known before. How strange it is when some guys coming here have no idea from OpenSocial??? I don&rsquo;t know why. I thought this event is really interesting to exchange idea and information, and to hack but some guys don&rsquo;t have any idea to code an opensocial gadget :(.</p>

<p>Jemeri&rsquo;s presentation took about 1 hour, although there is some technical problems with newhanoian gadget, but it&rsquo;s clear and I really like his openness and clear voice. He took some pics and I will post them here when having it.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s time for lunch!!! No pizza as proposed in agenda :). But it&rsquo;s really good with bread, meat, vegetables, juices&hellip; Thank for your lunch, eXo, Jason, Google :).</p>

<p><strong>Preparing for lunch [full of food but no such pic captured]</strong></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3211/3126459089_a0703a11de.jpg?v=0">http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3211/3126459089_a0703a11de.jpg?v=0</a>" title="Preparing for lunch [full of food but no such pic captured]" ></p>

<p>After lunch we have some introduction: who you are, what you are working, your ideas..blah blah. Just everything you would like to talk, to share.</p>

<p>Coming back to hacking time. Just learn to code following a gadget example: place searching. It&rsquo;s fun, but I knew some guys did not complete or like it. Some guys said they have no idea about javascript so it&rsquo;s really hard for them to follow.</p>

<p><strong>Hacking time</strong></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3088/3127289804_a93ff9ee3a.jpg?v=0">http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3088/3127289804_a93ff9ee3a.jpg?v=0</a>" title="Hacking time" ></p>

<p>After the gadget example, we have an idea sharing section to talk with people about your idea of an gadget (social app). How strange to me when just me sharing it :(. What about others'???</p>

<p>A strange and repetitive question: &ndash; How to config my server to host opensocial app??? It&rsquo;s a really big question to answer. You have to meet some social standards, implementing opensocial api, any may other things. Currently, I think it&rsquo;s really hard for so-called Vietnamese social network to implement OpenSocial api.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a little sad to me when it ended too early, about 4 P.M &ndash; 2 hours earlier than expected. Why? Because it seems that some guys would like to code, some guys don&rsquo;t, perhaps they didn&rsquo;t have any idea to code an gadget??</p>

<p>One interesting thing, as usually every developer will get a T-shirt. But here we can get 2 T-shirt. A black one from Google D3vF3st, a white one from <a href="http://teevn.com">http://teevn.com</a> :). So interesting!!! But unlucky me, I got 2 L-size ones. I could not find M-size one :(. If only I could be more bigger&hellip;</p>

<p>Thank you, Jeremi for your friendly hand-shake ;), your openness; thank you all guys for coming. I really like and love it :)</p>

<p>See more pics here from Jeremi: <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/jeremi/sets/72157611434836951/">http://flickr.com/photos/jeremi/sets/72157611434836951/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
