<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[blog.hoatle.info]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T17:21:25+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[hoatle]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[extended deadline for Barcamp Hanoi 2009 logo design contest]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/26/extended-deadline-for-barcamp-hanoi-2009-logo-design-contest/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-26T23:32:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/26/extended-deadline-for-barcamp-hanoi-2009-logo-design-contest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The 1st submission to Barcamp Hanoi 2009 Logo Design Contest:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3541/3307608039_9a27531d47.jpg?v=0" title="The 1st submission to Barcamp Hanoi 2009 Logo Design Contest" ></p>

<p>At present we are having some logo submitted for the contest and we know that the time seems so
short for you all to complete your logo for submission.</p>

<p>After great 2nd Barcamp Hanoi organizer meetup tonight, the Logo Design Contest submission deadline
is extended to:</p>

<p><code>Saturday, March 21st, 11:59 PM (GMT+7)</code></p>

<p>So you will have more than 3 weeks from now to prepare. But don’t waste your time, start your work
right now!</p>

<p>Thanks for joining and we are looking for your great Logo for BarCamp Hanoi 2009.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[lùi hạn tham dự Cuộc thi Thiết kế Logo Barcamp Hà Nội 2009]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/26/lui-han-tham-du-cuoc-thi-thiet-ke-logo-barcamp-ha-noi-2009/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-26T23:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/26/lui-han-tham-du-cuoc-thi-thiet-ke-logo-barcamp-ha-noi-2009</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Logo đầu tiên gửi đến cuộc thi:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3541/3307608039_9a27531d47.jpg?v=0" title="Logo đầu tiên gửi đến cuộc thi" ></p>

<p>Hiện tại chúng tôi đã nhận được những logo đầu tiên gửi đến để tham dự cuộc thi và chúng tôi cũng
biết là thời gian hơi gấp rút để bạn có thể hoàn thành tác phẩm của mình đúng thời hạn.</p>

<p>Sau cuộc họp lần 2 của ban tổ chức vừa rồi, hạn nộp logo dự thi sẽ được lùi lại đến:</p>

<p><code>Thứ bảy ngày 21 tháng 3 năm 2009 , 11:59 PM (Giờ GMT+7)</code></p>

<p>Vì vậy các bạn có hơn 3 tuần kể từ bây giờ để chuẩn bị. Nhưng đừng lãng phí thời gian, hãy bắt đầu
công việc ngay từ bây giờ!</p>

<p>Chúng tôi rất cám ơn bạn đã tham gia và đang chờ đợi những Logo ưng ý nhất của bạn dành cho
BarCamp Hanoi 2009.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OSDE - môi trường tuyệt vời cho các nhà phát triển ứng dụng OpenSocial]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/22/osde-moi-truong-tuyet-voi-cho-cac-nha-phat-trien-ung-dung-opensocial/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-22T23:06:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/22/osde-moi-truong-tuyet-voi-cho-cac-nha-phat-trien-ung-dung-opensocial</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Vừa chiều nay xong vào twitter search về opensocial, thấy mọi người đang rất quan tâm đến OpenSocia
weekendapps. Tự dưng thấy có cái link đến project này: OSDE &ndash; OpenSocial Development Environment và
yêu ngay tắp lự. Dự án là một module cho Eclipse để phát triển các ứng dụng OpenSocial trên môi
trường phát triển của các nhà phát triển.</p>

<p>Tớ vẫn còn nhớ cách đây hơn tháng vẫn code ứng dụng rồi test luôn trên các container thật như orkut,
hi5, myspace, friendster&hellip; nhưng rồi chẳng hiểu sao chỉ test được mỗi trên orkut :|. Khi đăng kí
trên các mạng này, để test ứng dụng của mình, bạn phải đăng kí, kết bạn [để test:)] và sau đó tiến
hành test và nhờ các friend-tester của mình test cho nhau :)).</p>

<p>Theo tớ đây là những bước nhàm chán và thực sự không phải cách pro trong phát triển ứng dụng. Bạn sẽ
test ứng dụng của mình như thế nào khi không có kết nối internet? OSDE chính là giải pháp hoàn hảo
và thực sự là module tuyệt vời cho Eclipse để phát triển các ứng dụng OpenSocial.</p>

<p>Bạn còn chờ gì nữa, project đó đây và hãy phát triển những ứng dụng OpenSocial tuyệt vời cho cộng
đồng nhé: <a href="http://www.eisbahn.jp/trac/osde/">http://www.eisbahn.jp/trac/osde/</a></p>

<p>Tuyệt vời, không thể nói gì hơn :). Thực sự có module này mình hào hứng hơn để phát triển các ứng
dụng OpenSocial. Code cho vui ý mà, hè hè ;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OSDE - great for OpenSocial developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/22/osde-great-for-opensocial-developers/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-22T22:53:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/22/osde-great-for-opensocial-developers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This afternoon I just hit with this project: OSDE &ndash; OpenSocial Developement Environment and loved it
at first sight :). This project is awesome for OpenSocial developers to work on their own
environment. I remembered on the first days of developing app, registered all opensocial containers,
make friends [for test :)] and then test the app. Somehow boring steps and not the pro way of app
development. What if you can not have internet connnection but you still want to test you opensocial
app. OSDE &ndash; OpenSocial Developement Environment is our solution. This is a great module for
Eclipse :).</p>

<p>Click on this link and let&rsquo;s create great apps: <a href="http://www.eisbahn.jp/trac/osde/">http://www.eisbahn.jp/trac/osde/</a></p>

<p>Everything there is good enough to code, much more easier to have your app in development stage :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[cuộc thi thiết kế logo cho Barcamp Hà Nội 2009]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/21/cuoc-thi-thiet-ke-logo-cho-barcamp-ha-noi-2009/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-21T15:14:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/21/cuoc-thi-thiet-ke-logo-cho-barcamp-ha-noi-2009</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.hoatle.info/images/barcamphanoismall2.png" title="Barcamp Hanoi 1 Logo" ></p>

<p>Logo hiện tại các bạn đang thấy ở phần đầu trang này là logo cũ của Barcamp Hanoi lần 1. Một vài
tháng trước, sau khi đặt logo này trên trang chủ, một số bạn đã góp ý nên thay logo cho Barcamp
Hanoi lần 2. Quan sát các Barcamp được tổ chức ở nơi khác, logo cũng được thiết kế mới cho mỗi sự
kiện hàng năm. Vì vậy những người chịu trách nhiệm tổ chức Barcamp Hanoi 2009 quyết định tổ chức một
cuộc thi thiết kế logo nhỏ. Logo thắng cuộc sẽ được sử dụng để in trên các băng rôn, T-shirt, trên
các tài liệu chính thức và sử dụng trên trang chủ. Các bạn có thể tìm hiểu thêm chi tiết về cuộc thi
ngay dưới đây:</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Cuộc thi thiết kế logo Barcamp Hà Nội 2009</h2>

<p>Nhằm mục đích giúp Barcamp Hanoi 2009 có một logo độc đáo và ý nghĩa.</p>

<p><strong>Phần thưởng cho người thắng cuộc</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Logo thắng cuộc và tác giả sẽ được thông báo rộng rãi để cộng đồng biết đến.</p></li>
<li><p>Một T-shirt miễn phí có in logo thắng cuộc.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Hướng dẫn</strong></p>

<p>Logo nên có những đặc điểm sau:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Thể hiện được tinh thần của Barcamp (Các bạn có thể bắt đầu bằng cách sử dụng file chuẩn logo
Barcamp ở đây)</p></li>
<li><p>Độc đáo, dễ nhận biết, có nét đặc trưng (Đây là logo của Barcamp Hanoi chứ không phải một Barcamp
chung chung)</p></li>
<li><p>Giữ được thẩm mĩ khi sử dụng dưới các hình thức khác nhau: trên web, băng rôn, T-shirt,…</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Tham khảo:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>File chuẩn Logo Barcamp <a href="http://barcamp.org/SpreadBarCamp">http://barcamp.org/SpreadBarCamp</a></p></li>
<li><p>Các mẫu logo ví dụ <a href="http://barcamp.org/LogoGallery">http://barcamp.org/LogoGallery</a></p></li>
<li><p>Barcamp Saigon 2008 Logo <a href="http://www.barcampsaigon.org/dokuwiki/doku.php?id=2008_org_logo">http://www.barcampsaigon.org/dokuwiki/doku.php?id=2008_org_logo</a></p></li>
<li><p>Barcamp Logos trên Google Image search <a href="http://images.google.com/images?q=Barcamp%20logo&amp;oe=utf-8&amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:unofficial&amp;client=firefox-a&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;sa=N&amp;hl=en&amp;tab=wi">http://images.google.com/images?q=Barcamp%20logo&amp;oe=utf-8&amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:unofficial&amp;client=firefox-a&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;sa=N&amp;hl=en&amp;tab=wi</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Tham dự cuộc thi thế nào?</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Đầu tiên hãy thiết kế một vài mẫu logo của riêng bạn. Bạn có thể đọc phần hướng dẫn ở trên để biết
thêm chi tiết.</p></li>
<li><p>Tải tác phẩm của bạn lên Flickr group <code>Barcamp Hanoi 2009 Logo Design Contest</code>.</p></li>
<li><p>Sau một tuần, các logo sẽ được đặt lên trang chủ của Barcamp Hanoi để bầu chọn công khai. Chính
các bạn quyết định logo nào sẽ được sử dụng cho Barcamp Hanoi 2009!</p></li>
<li><p>Logo thắng cuộc sẽ được sử dụng trên băng rôn, T-shirt, các tài liệu và trên web để quảng bá cho
Barcamp Hanoi 2009</p></li>
<li><p>Nếu bạn có bất cứ thắc mắc gì, có thể comment ngay vào bài viết này.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Các nguyên tắc gửi tác phẩm</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Bạn có thể gửi nhiều hơn một mẫu thiết kế</p></li>
<li><p>Mẫu tải lên dưới định dạng JPG/GIF/PNG tuy nhiên bạn vẫn phải chuẩn bị phiên bản độ phân giải
cao/dạng vector để phục vụ công tác in ấn nếu như bạn thắng cuộc.</p></li>
<li><p>Khi gửi tác phẩm lên tức là bạn sẵn sàng bỏ quyền tác giả của mình với tác phẩm và đóng góp bản
thiết kế của mình cho cộng đồng.</p></li>
<li><p>Đánh dấu logo của bạn với cụm từ  “BCHN 2009 LContest” để những người chịu trách nhiệm tổ chức có
thể biết đến tác phẩm của bạn nhanh hơn.</p></li>
<li><p>Tham gia vào Flickr group Barcamp Hanoi 2009 Logo Design Contest và gửi tác phẩm của mình lên.</p></li>
<li><p>Hãy đảm bảo email đăng ký ở Flickr của bạn là email thường dùng. Điều này giúp việc liên lạc với
bạn thuận tiện hơn.</p></li>
<li><p>Đừng quên, Hạn cuối gửi logo dự thi là <strong>Thứ 7 28 tháng 2 11 giờ 59 phút tối (GMT+7)</strong>. Bạn có
<strong>một tuần</strong> để chuẩn bị, thiết kế và gửi dự thi. <strong>Hãy bắt đầu ngay bây giờ!</strong></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barcamp Hanoi 2009 logo design contest]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/21/barcamp-hanoi-2009-logo-design-contest/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-21T15:06:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/21/barcamp-hanoi-2009-logo-design-contest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.hoatle.info/images/barcamphanoismall2.png" title="Barcamp Hanoi 1 Logo" ></p>

<p>The current logo you’re seeing on top of this page is the logo of Barcamp Hanoi 1. Several months
ago, right after we put it on the homepage,  some people gave us feedback that we should change the
logo. And we see that other Barcamps also change their logo for each individual event. So we think
it’s right time now to announce a tiny logo design contest for Barcamp Hanoi 2009. Then we can use
the winning logo to print banner, T-shirt, official documents and put it on the homepage. You can
read more detail about the contest below:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong>Barcamp Hanoi 2009 Logo Design Contest</strong></p>

<p>Help Barcamp Hanoi create a unique and meaningful logo for the event of 2009.</p>

<p><strong>Reward for the Winner</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Community-Wide recognition for designing the official Barcamp Hanoi 2009 logo featured on the
official homepage.</p></li>
<li><p>A free Barcamp Hanoi 2009 T-Shirt to show off your winning design.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Submission deadline</strong></p>

<p><code>Saturday, February 28th, 11:59 PM (GMT+7)</code></p>

<p><strong>Design Guidelines</strong></p>

<p>The logo should:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Convey the concept of Barcamp (You can use the starting files here)</p></li>
<li><p>Be distinct, unique and easily identifiable (It’s the logo of Barcamp Hanoi, not a general Barcamp)</p></li>
<li><p>Aesthetically fit in with a broad range of site/application designs</p></li>
</ul>


<p>References:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Starting files <a href="http://barcamp.org/SpreadBarCamp">http://barcamp.org/SpreadBarCamp</a></p></li>
<li><p>Sample logos <a href="http://barcamp.org/LogoGallery">http://barcamp.org/LogoGallery</a></p></li>
<li><p>Barcamp Saigon 2008 Logo <a href="http://www.barcampsaigon.org/dokuwiki/doku.php?id=2008_org_logo">http://www.barcampsaigon.org/dokuwiki/doku.php?id=2008_org_logo</a></p></li>
<li><p>Barcamp Logos on Google Image search <a href="http://images.google.com/images?q=Barcamp%20logo&amp;oe=utf-8&amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:unofficial&amp;client=firefox-a&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;sa=N&amp;hl=en&amp;tab=wi">http://images.google.com/images?q=Barcamp%20logo&amp;oe=utf-8&amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:unofficial&amp;client=firefox-a&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;sa=N&amp;hl=en&amp;tab=wi</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>How it works</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>First, create your Logo design. View the Design Guidelines for more details.</p></li>
<li><p>Upload your design to the contest-specific Flickr group <code>Barcamp Hanoi 2009 Logo Design Contest</code>
for review.</p></li>
<li><p>After a week, these designs will be posted online at the homepage of Barcamp Hanoi for public
voting. You determine the <strong>winner</strong>!</p></li>
<li><p>The winning Logo will be used on blog, websites, banners, documents and T-shirt to help promote
Barcamp Hanoi 2009.</p></li>
<li><p>If you have any additional questions, comment right below this post.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong> Submission &amp; Judging Criteria</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>You can submit more than one design.</p></li>
<li><p>Submissions can be made via JPG/GIF/PNG however please be prepared to provide high
resolution/vector graphic versions of your work.</p></li>
<li><p>As part of the submission, participants must be willing to give up all their rights to the
copyright and donate it to the community.</p></li>
<li><p>Tag your photo with the phrase “BCHN 2009 LContest“. This will allow us to search for and pull your
photo into a public image gallery.</p></li>
<li><p>Join the contest-specific Flickr group Barcamp Hanoi 2009 Logo Design Contest and add your image
to the image pool.</p></li>
<li><p>Make sure your Flickr account is linked to an active email address; this is the only means of
contacting the winner!</p></li>
<li><p>Don’t forget, <strong>the submission deadline is Saturday, February 28th, 11:59 PM (GMT+7)</strong>. You have a
week from now to prepare and submit your logo. <strong>Start right now!</strong></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barcamp Hanoi 2 will come soon :)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/20/barcamp-hanoi-2-will-come-soon/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-20T08:11:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/20/barcamp-hanoi-2-will-come-soon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone,</p>

<p>To tell the truth, I&rsquo;m a little envious of some HCM city (Saigon) geeks&#8217; activities, especially about Barcamp Saigon 1 and their #H3 :(. What about in Hanoi? Just correct me if I&rsquo;m wrong but it seem there
hasn&rsquo;t been any such interesting events in Hanoi. Here I just want to mention and introduce Barcamp Hanoi 2. You can just google some keyworks orderly to get info: barcamp to have general ideas about what is barcamp, barcampsaigon to know what Saigon geeks did to complete the task of organizing barcamp saigon 1. Then the last keywork is barcamphanoi to know more about Barcamp Hanoi organization status :). And then I will call for organizers + volunteers + participants + some more other things :)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Firstly, about Barcamp Hanoi 2. Why 2? Good question :P, do you know that Barcamp Hanoi 1 was first organized in Vietnam, esp. in Hanoi :). Just check this: <a href="http://blog.exoplatform.org/2007/12/28/barcamp-hanoi/">http://blog.exoplatform.org/2007/12/28/barcamp-hanoi/</a> So, Barcamp Hanoi 1 was organized by eXo employees (esp. by jeremi) just in internal eXo Platform SEA employees. And Now we (Hanoi geeks, bloggers, volunteers&hellip;) are organizing Barcamp Hanoi 2.</p>

<p>After the great success of Barcamp Saigon 1, some efforts to organize Barcamp Hanoi 2
started but in slow progress. Sometime it was supposed to happen before Tet holiday, then just some weeks after Tet holiday. But now we&rsquo;re still preparing for it and the progress is very fast. This post is also
for the purpose of preparation for Barcamp Hanoi 2. Please just check out what is happening in
Barcamp Hanoi 2 organization: <a href="http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en.">http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en.</a>
So here I&rsquo;m calling for organizers for Barcamp Hanoi 2 :). It&rsquo;s open to everyone :). Now the number of organizers can not be counted more than 10 and there are many things to do. Some points just remember: Just join in organizer team when you have passionation + know the spirit of barcamp :). Some volunteers needed for doing other things like food-prepare (don&rsquo;t worry, you do not have to cook any meal :P),
T-shirt design (for designers), sponsorship for persuasive speakers and many other things you can do for Barcamp Hanoi 2.</p>

<p>To participants: Know about barcamp spirit, know about barcamp rules, huh :P. No audience (exept for volunteers), just participants: think about what you will share for Barcamp Hanoi 2 (IT based topic),
and what topics you&rsquo;re interesting. We will have some forms to get info soon. We will make Barcamp Hanoi 2 as great and relaxed as possible. If too many people will go for registering Barcamp Hanoi 2, we will have
to filter out out some people :( because of time + venue + other problems.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Some expectations:</p>

<ul>
<li>What: call it Barcamp Hanoi 2 ;)</li>
<li>When: April 12 (supposed)</li>
<li>Where: RMIT Hanoi or Genetic BK or other?</li>
<li>Who: any one interested in joining barcamp, participants but not audience :)</li>
<li>How many people there: About 200 geeks. So think about some interesting topics to have your seat at Barcamp Hanoi 2. The seats are limited :)</li>
<li>official tag for Barcamp Hanoi 2: barcamphanoi</li>
<li>official website for Barcamp Hanoi 2 will be updated soon, just check it here <a href="http://barcamphanoi.org">http://barcamphanoi.org</a></li>
<li>Twitter to follow: <a href="http://twitter.com/barcamphanoi">http://twitter.com/barcamphanoi</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Links:</p>

<ul>
<li>Google group for organizers: <a href="http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en">http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en</a> (English)</li>
</ul>


<p>Hey, it&rsquo;s time for us to join Barcamp Hanoi 2. What you are waiting for? Spread the world about this event is a resprectedly helpful action.</p>

<p>Just ping some of us here to get more info:</p>

<ol>
<li>Hoat Le (<a href="http://hoatle.net">http://hoatle.net</a>)</li>
</ol>


<p>email: hoatlevan at gmail dot com</p>

<p>yahoo: wild_tiger8607</p>

<p>skype: hoatlevan</p>

<p>twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/hoatle">http://twitter.com/hoatle</a></p>

<p>Thanks for reading :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barcamp Hà Nội 2 đang tiến rất gần :)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/20/barcamp-ha-noi-2-dang-tien-rat-gan/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-20T05:27:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/20/barcamp-ha-noi-2-dang-tien-rat-gan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chào các anh-chị-em-bạn, nói tóm lại là chào mọi người :P
Tớ tên là Hoạt. Để biết thêm chi tiết google với từ khoá là hoatle hộ tớ với :).</p>

<p>Nói thật là tớ hơi ghen tị với một số hoạt động của các bạn ở thành phố HCM (tên dài :(, gọi là Sài Gòn nha), đặc biệt là Barcamp Saigon 1 và #H3 :(. Còn ở Hà Nội thì sao? Có phải là tớ sai khi nói rằng hầu như ở Hà Nội không có những hoạt động như thế này. Nhưng mà tớ xin chỉ nói và giới thiệu về Barcamp Hanoi 2 ở đây vì đây là topic cần nói, còn những cái khác tớ không đề cập thì các bạn có thể tự tìm hiểu thêm. Để biết thêm 1 số thông tin cần thiết trước khi đọc tiếp, bạn có thể tìm trên google với lần lượt những từ khoá sau đây: barcamp để tìm hiểu thông tin chung về barcamp, các quy tắc, phong cách&hellip;; tiếp đến là barcampsaigon để biết thêm thông tin về Barcamp Saigon 1, cách các bạn ở đấy tiến hành tổ chức và có các hoạt động gì, topic gì&hellip; Và từ khoá cuối cùng là barcamphanoi để biết thêm thông tin về tình hình tổ chức Barcamp Hanoi 2 lần này. Giới thiệu 1 chút về Barcamp Hanoi 2, tớ sẽ kêu gọi thêm 1 số bạn vào organizer team + tình nguyện + người tham dự cùng một số thứ linh tinh khác :P</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Đầu tiên là về Barcamp Hanoi 2. Tại sao lại là 2? Bạn có biết là Barcamp Hanoi 1 đã được tổ chức lần đầu tiên ở Việt Nam, đặc biệt hơn là ở Hà Nội. Tớ chắc chắn là rất ít người biết đến bởi vì bạn xem link sau <a href="http://blog.exoplatform.org/2007/12/28/barcamp-hanoi/.">http://blog.exoplatform.org/2007/12/28/barcamp-hanoi/.</a> Đấy, sẽ rất ít người biết bởi vì Barcamp Hanoi 1 được tổ chức nội bộ bởi nhân viên eXo Platform SEA, đặc biệt người đề xướng là jeremi. Còn bây giờ bọn tớ (Một số geek, blogger, tình nguyện ở Hà Nội) đang tổ chức Barcamp Hanoi 2.
Sau sự thành công của Barcamp Saigon 1 (<a href="http://barcampsaigon.org">http://barcampsaigon.org</a>), mới đầu Barcamp Hanoi 2 được khởi xướng và tiến hành nhưng với tốc độ khá chậm. Có lúc định ngày là trước tết cơ, xong không ổn lại bàn dồn ngày sau tết vài tuần. Nhưng đến giờ thì bọn tớ vẫn đang chuẩn bị cho nó. Tuy nhiên hiện quá trình chuẩn bị đang được gấp rút chuẩn bị, viết bài post này cũng là bước chuẩn bị đó. Để biết thêm thông tin về tình hình tổ chức Barcamp Hanoi 2, bạn có thể xem ở google group của nhóm tại: <a href="http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en.">http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en.</a></p>

<p>Giờ thì đến tiết mục kêu gọi thêm nhà tổ chức cho Barcamp Hanoi 2 :). Mọi người đều có thể tham gia.  Hiện tại số người tổ chức không quá 10 người và có rất nhiều thứ phải làm. Tuy nhiên để tham gia tổ chức bạn nên nhớ là: Chỉ tham gia vào đội tổ chức khi bạn thật sự hứng thú và biết về tinh thần của barcamp :). Bọn tớ cũng cần một số tình nguyện viên để cùng mọi người thực hiện những công việc khác như: chuẩn bị đồ ăn trưa (đừng lo, không ai phải vào bếp đâu mà sợ :P), thiết kế T-shirt hoặc Logo (cho dân thiết kế), đi xin tài trợ dành cho những bạn nói dễ thuyết phục, viết blog về sự kiện, viết bài đăng báo&hellip; và còn nhiều thứ khác nữa bạn có thể giúp Barcamp Hanoi 2.</p>

<p>Đối với các bạn tham dự: Biết về tinh thần của barcamp, biết về quy tắc của barcamp, ok :P. Không có người nghe (trừ những tình nguyện viên), còn lại đều phải là người tham gia: hãy nghĩ về chủ đề bạn sẽ nói ở Barcamp Hanoi 2 lần này (liên quan IT). Bọn tớ sẽ có 1 số form điền thông tin sớm nhất có thể ;). Bọn tớ sẽ cố gắng chuẩn bị và làm cho Barcamp Hanoi 2 càng đông, càng vui càng tốt. Nếu như có quá nhiều người đăng kí tham gia Barcamp Hanoi 2, bọn tớ rất tiếc sẽ phải loại bỏ để có đủ số người dự tính (khoảng 200) vì lí do thời gian + địa điểm + nhiều vấn đề khác nữa.</p>

<p>Một số dự tính:</p>

<ul>
<li>What: Sự kiện này là Barcamp Hanoi nha ;)</li>
<li>When: Có thể là ngày 12 tháng 4.</li>
<li>Where: Chưa biết được, có thể là RMIT Hanoi hoặc Genetic BK hoặc địa điểm khác?</li>
<li>Who: Bất kì ai quan tâm và muốn tham gia barcamp, tất nhiên là người tham gia chứ không phải là khán giả nha :)</li>
<li>Bao nhiêu người ở đấy: Khoảng 200 người. Bạn hãy nghĩ về chủ đề thú vị để còn có suất ở Barcamp Hanoi 2 chứ. Số ghế là có hạn.</li>
<li>Tag chính thức cho tất tần tật những gì liên quan đến Barcamp Hanoi: barcamphanoi</li>
<li>Website chính thức sẽ đang được cập nhật: <a href="http://barcamphanoi.org">http://barcamphanoi.org</a></li>
<li>Folllow twitter để được update những thông tin mới nhất: <a href="http://twitter.com/barcamphanoi">http://twitter.com/barcamphanoi</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Đấy, đã đến lúc mọi người tham gia Barcamp Hanoi 2 rồi. Bạn còn chờ gì nữa? Ít nhất thì bạn cũng tham gia và giúp đỡ Barcamp Hanoi 2 rất nhiều khi cho bạn bè, mọi người biết về Barcamp Hanoi 2.</p>

<p>Liên kết:
&ndash; Google group cho các bạn tổ chức thảo luận: <a href="http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en">http://groups.google.com.vn/group/barcamphanoi?hl=en</a></p>

<p>Nếu cần biết thêm thông tin, liên lạc với bọn tớ:</p>

<ol>
<li>Lê Văn Hoạt (<a href="http://hoatle.net">http://hoatle.net</a>)</li>
</ol>


<p>email: hoatlevan at gmail dot com</p>

<p>yahoo: wild_tiger8607</p>

<p>skype: hoatlevan</p>

<p>twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/hoatle">http://twitter.com/hoatle</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ngày làm việc đầu tiên ở eXo Platform SEA]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/17/ngay-lam-viec-dau-tien-o-exo-platform-sea/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-17T03:11:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/17/ngay-lam-viec-dau-tien-o-exo-platform-sea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hôm nay là ngày làm việc đầu tiên cho eXo Platform SEA, làm việc ở đây hơi bị ổn :). Từ tết đến giờ mới lại viết blog, một phần vì bận, 1 phần vì chuyển mạng qua fpt nhưng lại không được vì max thuê bao, lại quay lại dùng mạng của vietel, chậm kinh khủng, 1 máy down film cái là mạng không chạy được luôn => lại bị hạn chế down film :(. Giờ mọi thứ gần như trở lại bình thường thì hoạt động viết blog sẽ trở lại bình thường. Sắp tới có lẽ viết nhiều về Java + các sản phẩm của eXo vì làm việc nhiều với nó mà :).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Được làm việc ở eXo<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> cũng là may mắn, có bao giờ (dám) nghĩ là sẽ là việc ở đây đâu vì ở eXo không tuyển part-time mà hầu như các công ty cũng không tuyển part-time đâu. May mắn được biết và có một số trao đổi với Jeremi<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> từ sau đợt Opensocial Hackathon Hà Nội<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>. Sau hackathon, tớ có liên lạc với Jeremi và hẹn một buổi cafe ở eXo xem Jeremi có giúp gì được tớ không. Tớ cũng chỉ nghĩ là tới gặp nói chuyện làm quen, nhưng sau đó Jeremi có hỏi về việc học, về kinh nghiệm, gợi ý cho tớ làm technical document writer cho eXo. Quá tốt, tớ cũng cần đi làm + sang kì tới thực tập ở Bách Khoa rồi, đi thực tập phải làm gì liên quan đến tiếng Anh => vị trí này là ổn rồi, kì tới cứ thế mà tiếp tục làm chứ chả lo phải đi liên hệ thực tập nữa :)). Tuy được Jeremi gợi ý + giúp như vậy nhưng cũng chỉ là bước đầu chuẩn bị thôi. Sau đó là nộp CV, có bài test tiếng Anh nhẹ nhàng, tiếp theo là phỏng vấn 2 lượt, lượt thứ nhất với 3 anh để kiểm tra kiến thức về Java (chưa nhớ được tên anh này), kiến thức về OpenSocial (anh Tùng) và kỹ năng viết tài liệu (anh Công). Phỏng vấn lượt 2 tiếp theo là với Brice Revenant<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> &ndash; giám đốc eXo Platform SEA hồi trước tết. Về quê nghỉ tết rồi thì nhận được email cần test thêm: gửi tài liệu mẫu hướng dẫn về Community Management cho eXo Portal. Tết bận, tranh thủ viết lúc đêm, tối hôm sau ra hàng cafe internet gửi luôn :). Tết về nhà bán hàng bận, đúng chỉ có đêm mới được sờ đến máy tính :)). Cũng may mắn là mọi thứ đều ổn, rất là vui khi làm việc ở đây :).</p>

<p>Năm đen đủi cũng qua rồi, năm ngoái thật sự mệt mỏi, mất đồ, bị lừa, khó khăn :(. Bị lừa khi giúp bạn tìm việc, bị lừa qua bọn môi giới nhà đất, 1 tháng chuyển nhà đến 3-4 lần ý :( [hận + ghét nhất là bọn môi giới), xe máy thì bị mất nữa (phải mất 1 năm làm việc mình mới có thể kiếm lại những gì đã mất :(, chắc cuối năm nay ra trường lại mua 1 cái khác). Sống ở Hà Nội điên loạn, nguy hiểm [thành phố vì hoà bình ư? Điên loạn, nguy hiểm trong hoà bình thì đúng hơn :))]. Kì 2 đại học cũng mất luôn con cào cào mới đi được 3 tháng :(. Nhưng tất cả đã qua, giờ là thời điểm của năm mới may mắn: đầu năm thì ứng dụng music-engine của tớ đạt giải nhì trong cuộc thi viết ứng dụng OpenSocial khi vực Đông Nam Á<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup> &ndash; ứng dụng không phải là lớn nhưng sẽ là bàn đạp để tớ tiếp tục phát triển nó :). Có một số đề nghị tham gia các team, nhưng mà phải từ chối vì đã nhận lời làm ở eXo rồi. Đấy, lúc tìm việc mãi không ra, đến khi tìm được rồi lại thế đấy :)). Nói chung là kiểu này chả sợ thất nghiệp, kể cả trong thời kì suy thoái kinh tế thế giới thế này :). Barcamp Hà Nội 2 vẫn đang được chuẩn bị, eXo sẽ là một trong những nhà tài trợ chính. Có vẻ như quá trình chuẩn bị cho Barcamp Hà Nội 2 rất chậm, thông tin rất ít, mà không thấy có organizer nào nữa ngoài @xoài &ndash; Ninh Nguyen :(. Tớ sẽ trao đổi thêm với Brice, nếu được tạo điều kiện về thời gian sẽ cố gắng tham gia tổ chức cho Barcamp, còn không thì cũng sẽ bằng cách này hay cách khác tìm người cùng tổ chức, lên kế hoạch&hellip; Sau đó tớ cũng dự định sẽ có có 1 section, nhưng chưa biết về cái gì đây :D. Sang năm sẽ là một năm chuyển đổi lớn, có nhiều thời gian hơn sau khi tốt nghiệp ở trường + học xong ở HN-Aptech. Mệt thêm năm nay nữa thôi: Sáng học ở trường (5/7) + Chiều đi làm (5/7) + Tối học ở HN-Aptech(4/7). Học xong về ăn cơm + ngủ khoảng 3-4 tiếng. Sau đó dậy làm đủ các mọi việc: làm bài + duyệt web + viết blog&hellip;</p>

<p>Mấy hôm đầu chưa phải làm gì, được training để hiểu các sản phẩm, cách dùng&hellip; Mai training tiếp về WebOS sau đó là có 1 bài test kiểm tra chất lượng :). Mọi người ở đây đều cởi mở + tốt nữa. Được biết thêm 1 số anh chị nữa: anh Tùng (eXo Social project leader) và anh Trọng (Portal team leader) từ Hackathon, anh Công (tester) từ buổi phỏng vấn, chị Nga (document writer) và chị Hằng (training cho tớ + 1 anh nữa mới đến).
Đội hình đội ngũ ở đây [chưa cập nhật nên chưa thấy cái mặt tớ :))] <a href="http://wiki.exoplatform.org/xwiki/bin/view/Main/Team.">http://wiki.exoplatform.org/xwiki/bin/view/Main/Team.</a></p>

<p>Hôm nay buổi đầut tiên cũng có trao đổi với Brice về công việc, tớ có thể switch đến vị trí developer hoặc các vị trí khác nếu có khả năng :), còn ít nhất là nên làm 2 tháng viết docs để tìm hiểu các sản phẩm trước đã.
Jeremi làm việc cho eXo gần 2 năm, chuẩn bị mở công ty riêng ở Trung Quốc với 1 số bạn ở Thái Lan. Jeremi tốt + giỏi + cao-to-đẹp-zai; bạn girl nào cần giới thiệu thì tớ cũng không giới thiệu đâu vì Jeremi có bạn gái là người mẫu rồi thì phải :).</p>

<p>Một năm bận rộn + đầy hứa hẹn, Yeah :)</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://exoplatform.com<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>http://jeremi.info<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/14/opensocial-hackathon-ha-noi/<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/dir/brice/revenant<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/15/cuoc-thi-viet-ung-dung-opensocial-khu-vuc-dong-nam-a/<a href="#fnref:5" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[my first working day at eXo Platform SEA]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/17/my-first-working-day-at-exo-platform-sea/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-17T02:06:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2009/02/17/my-first-working-day-at-exo-platform-sea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is my first working day at eXo Platform SEA, a nice start working day :). Hey, so long no post from my blog sice Tet holiday, now I will blog more often.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;m the lucky one to have chance working at eXo<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> , I&rsquo;ve never thought about it before knowing and meeting Jeremi<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> since Opensocial Hackathon in Hanoi<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>. After the hackathon, Jeremi and I had some discussion, he just introduced me to apply for a position at eXo &ndash; a position where my English learning at HUT and computer learning at HN-Aptech meets, so the best position is document writer. I have some good points of writing English, I will write technical documents for eXo, nice and thank Jeremi so much! Though, this is just the very first step to join eXo. I had English test, interview with 3 guys to check general Java knowledge, openSocial knowledge (Tung) and document writing skill (Cong) and then continue my interview with Brice Revenant<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> &ndash; manager at eXo Platform SEA before our Tet holiday. I had another more test for writing a sample of user guide for comminity management when I was home. Lucky me, everything was nice and today I&rsquo;m very pleased to have my first working day and now blogging about it :).</p>

<p>The unlucky year passed by, last year I lost many things and had so many hardships: I was cheated when helping my friend finding a job, cheated to get address for renting, my motorbike was stolen (I will work hard to buy another by the end of this year), so living in Hanoi is really really dangerous [dangerous in peaceful :))], so I should be more and more and more careful. My bike was stolen at the second term at HUT, too :(. Now the new time for new year: my OpenSocial App took second prize at SE Asia OpenSocial Application contest, however, it is still in developement, hope to release it soon. Got some job offers which is very nice at the time of the world economic meltdown :D. Barcamp Hanoi 2 is being prepared, eXo will be one of the sponsers. I hope that I will have more time to wake everything up, Barcamp Hanoi 2 now seems slow in progress, I&rsquo;m preparing to have a session for Barcamp, too :). Next year will be my next big one after university graduation, more time for work, for meetup :).</p>

<p>Today I had some training to have basic ideas about Portal, how to use and organize it, cool ;). Tomorrow I will have training about WebOS and after that a test will come to check for understanding. Everyone here is nice! I just know some more guys: Tung (eXo Social project leader) and Trong (Portal team leader) from Hackathon, Cong (tester) from the interview, Nga (document writer) and Hang (give me and another guy training) &ndash; today. You can see more staffs here: <a href="http://wiki.exoplatform.org/xwiki/bin/view/Main/Team.">http://wiki.exoplatform.org/xwiki/bin/view/Main/Team.</a></p>

<p>Love this busy and promising year :)</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://exoplatform.com/<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>http://jeremi.info<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/13/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/dir/brice/revenant<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[music-engine indexer testing]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/17/music-engine-indexer-testing/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-17T00:34:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/17/music-engine-indexer-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just the time for test Indexer, input is a link to play a song, output is info of that song. Currently, I am testing some other music sites and coding for music-engine on the server-side.</p>

<p>You can test the Indexer at: <a href="http://musicengine.byethost13.com/">http://musicengine.byethost13.com/</a></p>

<p>Free host :).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[testing indexer]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/17/testing-indexer/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-17T00:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/17/testing-indexer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Test Indexer, input là link play 1 bài hát, output là info của bài hát đó. Hiện đang test dần 1 số trang nhạc, vừa code Indexer vừa code bên server cho music-engine.</p>

<p>Bạn có thể test thử cái Indexer tại địa chỉ: <a href="http://musicengine.byethost13.com/">http://musicengine.byethost13.com/</a></p>

<p>Host free :).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[giới thiệu cái music-engine nào]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/16/gioi-thieu-cai-music-engine-nao/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-16T12:13:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/16/gioi-thieu-cai-music-engine-nao</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cũng suy nghĩ khá nhiều để viết 1 cái ứng dụng OpenSocial và cuối cùng tớ đi đến quyết định viết cái ứng dụng music-engine này.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Music-engine nghĩa là thế nào? Music-engine của tớ sẽ đi tìm càng nhiều thông tin về các ca khúc càng tốt (tên, ca sĩ, nhạc sĩ, link nhạc&hellip;) và sắp xếp lại vào cơ sở dữ liệu trên Google Apps.</p>

<p>Music-engine sẽ cung cấp dịch vụ cho các ứng dụng OpenSocial của tớ. Người dùng có thể tìm kiếm, nghe, download, tạo và lưu playlist ưa thích. Ngoài ra, với tính năng của mạng xã hội, người dùng còn có thể gửi tặng ca khúc, playlist yêu thích cho bạn bè.</p>

<p>Mỗi người dùng sẽ có riêng 1 kênh (có thể tự động) cập nhật những bài hát họ đang nghe. Giống như Twitter trả lời câu hỏi &ldquo;bạn đang làm gì?&rdquo; thì với Music-Engine thì bạn sẽ trả lời câu hỏi &ldquo;Bạn đang nghe gì?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Vẫn còn một số tính năng quan trọng nữa nhưng có lẽ để sau, phải hoàn thành sớm sớm còn đăng kí SE Asia Contest chứ ;))</p>

<p>Về vấn đề bản quyền? Music-engine sẽ chỉ tìm và lưu trữ thông tin chứ không lưu nhạc trên server (có muốn cũng chả được). Một số trang tìm kiếm có kiểu cache, tức là lưu file nhạc về máy chủ của mình. Việc này có phải là sao chép bất hợp pháp? Còn đối với Music-Engine, mọi hoạt động của người dùng như tìm kiếm, download hay các hoạt động khác thì đều từ phía người dùng, Music-Engine không có bất kì mối liên hệ nào cả :D.</p>

<p>Chỉ là một số ý tưởng để chia sẻ. Tớ đã hoàn thành cơ bản xong mô hình cơ sở dữ liệu cũng như thử nghiệm crawl xong 1 trang nhạc.</p>

<p>Vì Google Apps hiện tại chỉ hỗ trợ Python, thế nên hầu như sẽ code bằng Python trên server.</p>

<p>Vì tớ làm việc với PHP khá lâu và cũng có kinh nghiệm viết một cái news crawler mấy tháng trước. Bây giờ sẽ cải thiện cho nó thành music-crawler, không phải là news nữa.</p>

<p>Bạn nào thích code cùng thì cứ liên hệ. Còn nhiều thứ phải làm quá, dù gì thì đây cũng là dự án làm cho vui :).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[music-engine Intro]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/16/music-engine-intro/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-16T11:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/16/music-engine-intro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thinking so much about an OpenSocial apps and finally I decided to develop a music-engine application.</p>

<p>What is a music-engine? My music-engine will crawl and index as much as possible any songs in the Internet and reorganize it into datastore in Google Apps.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Music-engine will be the service provider allows me to write OpenSocial apps for any container. Users can search, listen, create and save their own favorite playlists. They can send that playlist to their friends as gifts.</p>

<p>Each user can have his own music-stream life. This is something like Twitter, but this just allows users to recommend any song they like.</p>

<p>These are just some critical features I will try to implement.</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s about copyright issue? Music-engine just crawles and indexes information, it doesn&rsquo;t store any music file on its own server. Every activity such as search, download or any other is from users.</p>

<p>Just some ideas about this. I have completed the database schema and a little about music-engine crawler.</p>

<p>As we know, Google Apps currently supports Python, so it will be coded in Python.</p>

<p>I love PHP, and I have some experience to write a news crawler some months ago. Now I will improve it for music, not news.</p>

<p>If anyone would like to code with me, please contact me. There are many things to do, this is just a project for fun :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSocial Hackathon Hà Nội]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/14/opensocial-hackathon-ha-noi/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-14T00:51:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/14/opensocial-hackathon-ha-noi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hôm nay khá là bận rộn :). Vừa ở eXo Platform về thì đi chơi ngay với mấy đứa bạn cùng lớp, lâu lắm rồi thì phải :(. Nhiều chuyện quá làm mình không thích đi chơi nhiều như ngày trước nữa.</p>

<p>Hôm nay tham gia OpenSocial Hackathon, được gặp một số bạn khá thú vị :).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Hôm nay bình minh của tớ bắt đầu lúc 9h. Cũng thường thôi :D, nếu mà không phải đi học hay đi thi vào buổi sáng thì đấy là lịch thường ngày của tớ. Không biết sao nhưng thực sự tớ rất thích làm việc qua đêm, bao giờ chán hoặc buồn ngủ mới thôi. Hôm qua đi ngủ lúc 4h. Cũng khó mà hiểu hết những việc tớ làm :). Chỉ làm những việc tớ thích với máy tính: viết blog, xây dựng website theo yêu cầu của khách &ndash; chỉ là những website nho nhỏ cho doanh nghiệp giới thiệu sản phẩm, giới thiệu công ty, đăng tin tức, nghịch lung tung với một số xu hướng công nghệ, như viết opensocial app chẳng hạn, nâng cao khả năng lập trình = cách code nhiều hơn, nghĩ nhiều hơn, còn nhiều nữa. Thích thì học thì làm, chỉ là thói quen.</p>

<p>Mất gần nửa tiếng mới đến được văn phòng eXo Platform ở tầng 7 số 11 Thái Hà (chính xác hơn là ngõ 11 Thái Hà). Có vẻ đến hơi sớm thì phải (lúc đó tầm 10 giờ 20&#8217;), đến mới thấy có 2 hoặc 3 anh gì đó (trừ những người bên eXo).</p>

<p><strong>Lúc sớm</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3208/3127289114_6c42ab2824.jpg?v=0" title="Lúc sớm" ></p>

<p>11 giờ là mọi người có vẻ đã đến đông đủ. Chỉ có khoảng hơn 20 người &ndash; con số khá khiêm tốn so với dự tính. Tớ cứ nghĩ là phải tầm 50 người cơ ;). Chỉ sợ đăng kí chậm không có chỗ, hóa ra tớ là người đăng kí thứ 3 trong danh sách :)</p>

<p><strong>Mọi người đến đông [chắc chưa đủ :D]</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3290/3127289274_56552c8884.jpg?v=0" title="Mọi người đến đông [chắc chưa đủ :D]" ></p>

<p>Ở đấy gặp bao nhiêu là người ở nhiều công ty khác nhau, trừ tớ, tớ hiện chưa làm cho công ty nào cả :), vẫn đang đi tìm, có vẻ nhiều công ty không có part-time job thì phải. Tớ không nhớ hết được tất cả mọi người, chỉ xin liệt kê một số công ty: eXo Platform (tất nhiên là có Jeremi Joslin, 3 người nữa mà tớ đã trao đổi khá nhiều với 2 anh ở eXo), Tinh Van Media (2 bạn sinh viên năm 3 của trường ĐH Công Nghệ Quốc Gia, mới đầu tớ gọi 2 cậu này = anh, sau thì đổi ngược lại khi biết tuổi nhau :))), Moore Corporation (<a href="http://nghenhac.info;">http://nghenhac.info;</a> <a href="http://anhso.net">http://anhso.net</a> &ndash; có 1 người), VinaLive (<a href="http://phununet.com">http://phununet.com</a> &ndash; mạng xã hội dành riêng cho phụ nữ; 3-4 người thì phải); 1 người bên Tầm Tay (<a href="http://tamtay.vn">http://tamtay.vn</a>). 2 người đến từ <a href="http://teevn.com.">http://teevn.com.</a> Àh, cả Jason nữa, cuối cùng thì cũng được biết mặt anh này :). Một anh Tây của <a href="http://newhanoian.xemzi.com.">http://newhanoian.xemzi.com.</a> Còn một số người khác nữa nhưng tớ không nhớ hết được.</p>

<p><strong>Đố biết tớ đâu? :)</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3196/3127290146_951883aa5b.jpg?v=0" title="Đố biết tớ đâu? :)" ></p>

<p>Jeremi có một bài thuyết trình khá rõ về OpenSocial, nhưng tớ nghĩ đây chỉ là giới thiệu cơ bản,
hầu như những gì Jeremi nói thì cũng đã tìm hiểu trước rồi. Nhưng lạ là một số người hình như đến
tham gia mà chưa biết gì về OpenSocial hay sao ý hoặc là rất mơ hồ về nó thì phải??? Tớ không biết
sao nữa. Tớ cứ nghĩ là đây thực sự là sự kiện rất thú vị để trao đổi kiến thức, thông tin và còn
hack nữa chứ :), nhưng mà một số người đến đây chỉ để xem hay sao ý, dường như không có ý tưởng để
viết một cái opensocial gadget thì phải, hoặc là không muốn chia sẻ???</p>

<p>Bài thuyết trình kéo dài khoảng một giờ đồng hồ. Mặc dù phần demo có một số vấn đề với newhanoian
gadget nhưng bài thuyết trình rất rõ ràng. Thực sự rất thích sự cởi mở và giọng nói tiếng Anh chậm,
rõ (Jeremi là người Pháp). Sẽ post một số ảnh ở đây khi Jeremi gửi ảnh cho tớ, vừa gửi email rồi.</p>

<p>Sau đấy là đến giờ ăn trưa!!! Không có pizza như trong agenda :), nhưng mà có bánh mì, thịt, rau,
hoa quả&hellip; ngon. Cảm ơn eXo, Jason, Google về bữa trưa :).</p>

<p><strong>Chuẩn bị cho bữa trưa [Đầy thức ăn nhưng mà không có cái ảnh nào như thế :)]</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3211/3126459089_a0703a11de.jpg?v=0" title="Chuẩn bị cho bữa trưa [Đầy thức ăn nhưng mà không có cái ảnh nào như thế :)]" ></p>

<p>Ăn trưa xong mọi người giới thiệu về mình: bạn là ai, bạn đang làm gì, ý tưởng của bạn..blah blah.
Mọi thứ bạn muốn nói và muốn chia sẻ.</p>

<p>Tiếp theo là đến lúc hack. Đầu tiên là học cách viết gadget bằng cách code theo một gadget mẫu:
place searching trên newhanoian. Khá hay, đơn giản nhưng tớ biết một số người có vẻ chưa hoàn thành
hoặc không thích lắm thì phải. Một số người nói là không sử dụng javascript, chính vì thế mà rất khó
để code cùng mọi người.</p>

<p><strong>Đến lúc hack :)</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3088/3127289804_a93ff9ee3a.jpg?v=0" title="Đến lúc hack :)" ></p>

<p>Sau khi code gadget mẫu, mọi người có phần chia sẻ ý tưởng và tìm người cùng code một gadget theo ý
tưởng đó. Lạ là có mỗi tớ lên chia sẻ ý tưởng của mình :(.</p>

<p>Có một câu hỏi khá lạ (lùng) và lặp đi lặp lại: &ndash; Làm sao để mạng xã hội của tôi có thể trở thành
một opensocial container? Cách config thế nào? Thực sự đây là một câu hỏi lớn. Để có thể trở thành
một opensocial container, mạng xã hội đó phải đáp ứng một số chuẩn của mạng xã hội, phải implement
hệ thống opensocial api và còn nhiều thứ khác nữa. Thực sự theo tớ nghĩ rất khó để &ldquo;cái-gọi-là&rdquo;
mạng xã hội ở Việt Nam có thể implement mọi thứ để trở thành một container cho các opensocial app
khi những người quản lý của các mạng này hỏi những câu hỏi như thế? Nếu có thời gian tìm hiểu chắc
sẽ không hỏi câu này đâu :)).</p>

<p>Cũng hơi buồn tí khi mà thời gian kết thúc khá sớm, khoảng 4h chiều &ndash; sớm hơn 2 giờ so với dự kiến.
Đây cũng là điều dễ hiểu thôi vì dường như một số người muốn code nhưng một số người thì không hoặc
là chưa sẵn sàng.</p>

<p>Một chi tiết khá thú vị. Thông thường những sự kiện như này thì mọi người sẽ được phát một chiếc
T-shirt đặc trưng, nhưng lần này mỗi người được 2 cái cơ ;)). Theo tớ để ý thì có khá nhiều T-shirt,
thừa hơi bị nhiều so với dự tính. Không có cảnh xô đẩy (thì phải) như D3vF3st ở t.p Hồ Chí Minh.
Mỗi người một chiếc màu đen truyền thống, một chiếc màu trắng của bên <a href="http://teevn.com.">http://teevn.com.</a> Nhưng rất
không may là tớ nhận được 2 chiếc đều cỡ L. Tìm mãi mà chả thấy cỡ M đâu cả. Giá mà mình to hơn 1 tí
thì tốt, đỡ phải kén chọn ;))&hellip;</p>

<p>Thực sự cảm ơn Jeremi vì cái bắt tay ;), vì sự cởi mở. Cảm on mọi người đã đến. Tớ thực sự thích
OpenSocial Hackathon Hanoi :)</p>

<p>Xem thêm ảnh: <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/jeremi/sets/72157611434836951/">http://flickr.com/photos/jeremi/sets/72157611434836951/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSocial Hackathon in Hanoi]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/13/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-13T23:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/13/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is one of the most active day of mine :). With the opensocial hackathon in Hanoi, I have
chance to meet some interesting people.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My morning started in 9 A.M (OMG!!! But it&rsquo;s my normal day; I don&rsquo;t know why but I&rsquo;d really like to
work at late night. Yesterday, I stopped working at about 4 A.M. It&rsquo;s hard to define my work :).
Just do everything with computer: blogging, building some requested websites from customers,
experimenting new technology trend, improve programming skill, oh many more. Just my habit :).</p>

<p>It took me about half an hour to get to eXo Platform office. Coming a bit early (about 10h 20&#8217;),
I just saw 2 or 3 geeks sitting there.</p>

<p><strong>Early time</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3208/3127289114_6c42ab2824.jpg?v=0" title="Early time" ></p>

<p>11h everyone came. It&rsquo;s just about more than 20 geeks &ndash; this number is less than my expectation ;). I thought there must have been about 50 geeks ;).</p>

<p><strong>Everyone came</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3290/3127289274_56552c8884.jpg?v=0" title="Everyone came" ></p>

<p>I met many geeks from many companies, except me, I&rsquo;m currently not working for any company :), just finding! I don&rsquo;t remember all, but just list some here: eXo Platform (of course, Jereme Joslin, 3 other guys and I have much talk with two of them), Tinh Van Media (<a href="http://xalo.vn;">http://xalo.vn;</a> two 3th-year students from College of Technology), Moore Corporation (<a href="http://nghenhac.info,">http://nghenhac.info,</a> <a href="http://anhso.net">http://anhso.net</a>), VinaLive (<a href="http://phununet.com;">http://phununet.com;</a> 3-4 guys), <a href="http://tamtay.vn">http://tamtay.vn</a> (one guy), guys from <a href="http://teevn.com.">http://teevn.com.</a> Ah, Jason &ndash; now I know him ;), and a guy from <a href="http://newhanoian.xemzi.com/.">http://newhanoian.xemzi.com/.</a> There are more guys but currently I can not remember all.</p>

<p><strong>Where am I? :)</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3196/3127290146_951883aa5b.jpg?v=0" title="Where am I? :)" ></p>

<p>Jeremi had a very clear presentation about OpenSocial, but I think it&rsquo;s just introduction, everything he said I have known before. How strange it is when some guys coming here have no idea from OpenSocial??? I don&rsquo;t know why. I thought this event is really interesting to exchange idea and information, and to hack but some guys don&rsquo;t have any idea to code an opensocial gadget :(.</p>

<p>Jemeri&rsquo;s presentation took about 1 hour, although there is some technical problems with newhanoian gadget, but it&rsquo;s clear and I really like his openness and clear voice. He took some pics and I will post them here when having it.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s time for lunch!!! No pizza as proposed in agenda :). But it&rsquo;s really good with bread, meat, vegetables, juices&hellip; Thank for your lunch, eXo, Jason, Google :).</p>

<p><strong>Preparing for lunch [full of food but no such pic captured]</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3211/3126459089_a0703a11de.jpg?v=0" title="Preparing for lunch [full of food but no such pic captured]" ></p>

<p>After lunch we have some introduction: who you are, what you are working, your ideas..blah blah. Just everything you would like to talk, to share.</p>

<p>Coming back to hacking time. Just learn to code following a gadget example: place searching. It&rsquo;s fun, but I knew some guys did not complete or like it. Some guys said they have no idea about javascript so it&rsquo;s really hard for them to follow.</p>

<p><strong>Hacking time</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3088/3127289804_a93ff9ee3a.jpg?v=0" title="Hacking time" ></p>

<p>After the gadget example, we have an idea sharing section to talk with people about your idea of an gadget (social app). How strange to me when just me sharing it :(. What about others&#8217;???</p>

<p>A strange and repetitive question: &ndash; How to config my server to host opensocial app??? It&rsquo;s a really big question to answer. You have to meet some social standards, implementing opensocial api, any may other things. Currently, I think it&rsquo;s really hard for so-called Vietnamese social network to implement OpenSocial api.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a little sad to me when it ended too early, about 4 P.M &ndash; 2 hours earlier than expected. Why? Because it seems that some guys would like to code, some guys don&rsquo;t, perhaps they didn&rsquo;t have any idea to code an gadget??</p>

<p>One interesting thing, as usually every developer will get a T-shirt. But here we can get 2 T-shirt. A black one from Google D3vF3st, a white one from <a href="http://teevn.com">http://teevn.com</a> :). So interesting!!! But unlucky me, I got 2 L-size ones. I could not find M-size one :(. If only I could be more bigger&hellip;</p>

<p>Thank you, Jeremi for your friendly hand-shake ;), your openness; thank you all guys for coming. I really like and love it :)</p>

<p>See more pics here from Jeremi: <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/jeremi/sets/72157611434836951/">http://flickr.com/photos/jeremi/sets/72157611434836951/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSocial Hackathon và BarCamp Hà Nội]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/25/opensocial-hackathon-va-barcamp-ha-noi/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-25T02:38:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/25/opensocial-hackathon-va-barcamp-ha-noi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tin dành cho các bạn ở Hà Nội. Như mọi người đã biết, Google DevFest HCMC &ndash; The First Ever Google
Hackathon Tour in Vietnam<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> (ngày 4/11/2008) và BarCamp Saigon<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> (November 5, 2008) đã được tổ
chức ở thành phố Hồ Chí Minh và nhiều bạn ở Hà Nội không tham gia được (tất nhiên trong đó có tớ :(,
dù gì thì những sự kiện như vậy không thể không tham gia).</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>OpenSocial Hackathon ở Hà Nội</h2>

<p>&ldquo;Sau khi tổ chức thành công Google Devfest<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> ở thành phố HCM hôm 4/11/2008 và rất nhiều bạn ở Hà
Nội đã không thể tham dự, chúng tôi dự định tổ chức một Hackathon nho nhỏ tập trung vào hệ thống API
của OpenSocial. Các kỹ sư phần mềm của eXo Platform<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> (cùng với đội ngũ Google Devfest khu vực Đông
Nam Á) sẽ tới trao đổi với mọi người, một số ứng dựng OpenSocial API ở các dịch vụ mạng xã hội Việt
Nam sẽ được demo. Một kỹ sư của Google khu vực Đông Nam Á sẽ tham gia. Ngày tổ chức dự kiến:
13/12/2008.&rdquo; (Nguồn Jason).</p>

<p>Lịch trình hôm 13/12/2008 tại OpenSocial Hackathon:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>10:30AM – 11:00AM : Đăng kí</p></li>
<li><p>11:00AM – 12:00PM : Bài thuyết trình về openSocial</p></li>
<li><p>12:00PM – 1:00PM : brainstorming + pizza</p></li>
<li><p>1:00PM – 5:00PM : Viết các ứng dụng openSocial</p></li>
<li><p>1:00PM – 2:00PM : Hướng dẫn viết gadget openSocial</p></li>
<li><p>5:00PM – 6:00PM : Thuyết trình tổng kết kết quả làm việc buổi chiều</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Xem thêm: <a href="http://blog.exoplatform.org/2008/11/24/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/">http://blog.exoplatform.org/2008/11/24/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/</a></p>

<p>Chỉ có 50 ghế dành cho ai đăng kí sớm nhất và được lựa chọn Đăng kí ngay.</p>

<h2>BarCamp Hà Nội đang được chuẩn bị</h2>

<p>Xem thêm <a href="http://wiki.barcamphanoi.org.">http://wiki.barcamphanoi.org.</a></p>

<p>Tuyệt vời!</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://jasonlog.supersized.org/archives/131-Google-DevFest-HCMC-The-First-Ever-Google-Hackathon-Tour-in-Vietnam.html<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>http://www.barcampsaigon.org/<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>http://code.google.com/events/apacdevfest/<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>http://www.exoplatform.com/portal/public/en/<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSocial Hackathon and BarCamp Hanoi]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/25/opensocial-hackathon-and-barcamp-hanoi/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-25T02:04:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/25/opensocial-hackathon-and-barcamp-hanoi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good news to Hanoi developers! As we know, Google DevFest HCMC &ndash; The First Ever Google Hackathon
Tour in Vietnam<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> (November 4, 2008) did succeed, BarCamp Saigon<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> (November 5, 2008) did succeed.
However, these two events was held in Ho Chi Minh city, many developers from Hanoi missed it.</p>

<p>Now you can join OpenSocial Hackathon and BarCamp Hanoi :).</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>OpenSocial Hackathon in Hanoi</h2>

<p>&ldquo;After the success of Google Devfest<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> in HCMC on November 4, 2008 and many talent developers in
Hanoi missed the Event, we plan to hold a mini Hackathon in Hanoi with focus on OpenSocial API.
Software engineers from eXo Platform<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> (going with Google Devfest team in Southeast Asia Tour) will
interact with Hanoi based devs and geeks, some demos of OpenSocial API apps on Vietnamese social
networking services should be showed. An engineer of Google Southeast Asia could join to assist the
participants. The planned date is December 13, 2008&rdquo; (from Jason).</p>

<p>Agenda on December 13, 2008:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>10:30AM – 11:00AM : Registration</p></li>
<li><p>11:00AM – 12:00PM : openSocial Presentation</p></li>
<li><p>12:00PM – 1:00PM : brainstorming + pizza</p></li>
<li><p>1:00PM – 5:00PM : Coding your openSocial applications</p></li>
<li><p>1:00PM – 2:00PM : guided walkthrough a first openSocial gadget</p></li>
<li><p>5:00PM – 6:00PM : presentation of what have been done in the afternoon.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>More info: <a href="http://blog.exoplatform.org/2008/11/24/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/">http://blog.exoplatform.org/2008/11/24/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/</a></p>

<p>Only 50 seats are available. Just register now.</p>

<h2>BarCamp Hanoi is on the way of preparation</h2>

<p>Get information and just don&rsquo;t miss it from <a href="http://wiki.barcamphanoi.org.">http://wiki.barcamphanoi.org.</a></p>

<p>Really interesting and good news!</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://jasonlog.supersized.org/archives/131-Google-DevFest-HCMC-The-First-Ever-Google-Hackathon-Tour-in-Vietnam.html<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>http://www.barcampsaigon.org/<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>http://code.google.com/events/apacdevfest/<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>http://www.exoplatform.com/portal/public/en/<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where is my Google SearchWiki???]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/23/where-is-my-google-searchwiki/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-23T09:36:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/23/where-is-my-google-searchwiki</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Where is the Google SearchWiki that is a new feature encouraging people to have search more with new
experience? Just 2 days after Google&rsquo;s announcement it&rsquo;s gone. Does it mean that SearchWiki is not
very helpful and Google decided to take it out?</p>

<p>Google says that this is a bug and is working on restoring SearchWiki now: “We’re really sorry that
people can’t use SearchWiki at the moment &ndash; we’re working to fix the problem as quickly as we can.
Please bear with us.”</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SearchWiki của Google đâu rồi???]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/23/searchwiki-cua-google-dau-roi/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-23T09:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/23/searchwiki-cua-google-dau-roi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tính năng xã hội mới có tính kích thích, tạo thêm trải nghiệm cho người dùng khi sử dụng bộ máy tìm
kiểm của Google đâu rồi? Chỉ sau hai ngày thì tính năng này không còn hoạt động nữa. Phải chăng
SearchWiki không thực sự hữu dụng và Google quyết định gỡ bỏ?</p>

<p>Theo Google lý do SearchWiki không hoạt động nữa là do SearchWiki có lỗi và họ đang cố gắng khắc
phục sự cố: &ldquo;Chúng tôi rất lấy làm tiếc khi người dùng hiện không thể sử dụng SearchWiki &ndash; chúng tôi
đang cố gắng hết sức khắc phục. Hãy thông cảm cho chúng tôi.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
