<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[blog.hoatle.info]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T07:34:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[hoatle]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[giới thiệu cái music-engine nào]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/16/gioi-thieu-cai-music-engine-nao/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-16T12:13:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/16/gioi-thieu-cai-music-engine-nao</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cũng suy nghĩ khá nhiều để viết 1 cái ứng dụng OpenSocial và cuối cùng tớ đi đến quyết định viết cái ứng dụng music-engine này.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Music-engine nghĩa là thế nào? Music-engine của tớ sẽ đi tìm càng nhiều thông tin về các ca khúc càng tốt (tên, ca sĩ, nhạc sĩ, link nhạc&hellip;) và sắp xếp lại vào cơ sở dữ liệu trên Google Apps.</p>

<p>Music-engine sẽ cung cấp dịch vụ cho các ứng dụng OpenSocial của tớ. Người dùng có thể tìm kiếm, nghe, download, tạo và lưu playlist ưa thích. Ngoài ra, với tính năng của mạng xã hội, người dùng còn có thể gửi tặng ca khúc, playlist yêu thích cho bạn bè.</p>

<p>Mỗi người dùng sẽ có riêng 1 kênh (có thể tự động) cập nhật những bài hát họ đang nghe. Giống như Twitter trả lời câu hỏi &ldquo;bạn đang làm gì?&rdquo; thì với Music-Engine thì bạn sẽ trả lời câu hỏi &ldquo;Bạn đang nghe gì?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Vẫn còn một số tính năng quan trọng nữa nhưng có lẽ để sau, phải hoàn thành sớm sớm còn đăng kí SE Asia Contest chứ ;))</p>

<p>Về vấn đề bản quyền? Music-engine sẽ chỉ tìm và lưu trữ thông tin chứ không lưu nhạc trên server (có muốn cũng chả được). Một số trang tìm kiếm có kiểu cache, tức là lưu file nhạc về máy chủ của mình. Việc này có phải là sao chép bất hợp pháp? Còn đối với Music-Engine, mọi hoạt động của người dùng như tìm kiếm, download hay các hoạt động khác thì đều từ phía người dùng, Music-Engine không có bất kì mối liên hệ nào cả :D.</p>

<p>Chỉ là một số ý tưởng để chia sẻ. Tớ đã hoàn thành cơ bản xong mô hình cơ sở dữ liệu cũng như thử nghiệm crawl xong 1 trang nhạc.</p>

<p>Vì Google Apps hiện tại chỉ hỗ trợ Python, thế nên hầu như sẽ code bằng Python trên server.</p>

<p>Vì tớ làm việc với PHP khá lâu và cũng có kinh nghiệm viết một cái news crawler mấy tháng trước. Bây giờ sẽ cải thiện cho nó thành music-crawler, không phải là news nữa.</p>

<p>Bạn nào thích code cùng thì cứ liên hệ. Còn nhiều thứ phải làm quá, dù gì thì đây cũng là dự án làm cho vui :).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[music-engine Intro]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/16/music-engine-intro/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-16T11:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/16/music-engine-intro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thinking so much about an OpenSocial apps and finally I decided to develop a music-engine application.</p>

<p>What is a music-engine? My music-engine will crawl and index as much as possible any songs in the Internet and reorganize it into datastore in Google Apps.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Music-engine will be the service provider allows me to write OpenSocial apps for any container. Users can search, listen, create and save their own favorite playlists. They can send that playlist to their friends as gifts.</p>

<p>Each user can have his own music-stream life. This is something like Twitter, but this just allows users to recommend any song they like.</p>

<p>These are just some critical features I will try to implement.</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s about copyright issue? Music-engine just crawles and indexes information, it doesn&rsquo;t store any music file on its own server. Every activity such as search, download or any other is from users.</p>

<p>Just some ideas about this. I have completed the database schema and a little about music-engine crawler.</p>

<p>As we know, Google Apps currently supports Python, so it will be coded in Python.</p>

<p>I love PHP, and I have some experience to write a news crawler some months ago. Now I will improve it for music, not news.</p>

<p>If anyone would like to code with me, please contact me. There are many things to do, this is just a project for fun :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSocial Hackathon Hà Nội]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/14/opensocial-hackathon-ha-noi/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-14T00:51:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/14/opensocial-hackathon-ha-noi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hôm nay khá là bận rộn :). Vừa ở eXo Platform về thì đi chơi ngay với mấy đứa bạn cùng lớp, lâu lắm rồi thì phải :(. Nhiều chuyện quá làm mình không thích đi chơi nhiều như ngày trước nữa.</p>

<p>Hôm nay tham gia OpenSocial Hackathon, được gặp một số bạn khá thú vị :).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Hôm nay bình minh của tớ bắt đầu lúc 9h. Cũng thường thôi :D, nếu mà không phải đi học hay đi thi vào buổi sáng thì đấy là lịch thường ngày của tớ. Không biết sao nhưng thực sự tớ rất thích làm việc qua đêm, bao giờ chán hoặc buồn ngủ mới thôi. Hôm qua đi ngủ lúc 4h. Cũng khó mà hiểu hết những việc tớ làm :). Chỉ làm những việc tớ thích với máy tính: viết blog, xây dựng website theo yêu cầu của khách &ndash; chỉ là những website nho nhỏ cho doanh nghiệp giới thiệu sản phẩm, giới thiệu công ty, đăng tin tức, nghịch lung tung với một số xu hướng công nghệ, như viết opensocial app chẳng hạn, nâng cao khả năng lập trình = cách code nhiều hơn, nghĩ nhiều hơn, còn nhiều nữa. Thích thì học thì làm, chỉ là thói quen.</p>

<p>Mất gần nửa tiếng mới đến được văn phòng eXo Platform ở tầng 7 số 11 Thái Hà (chính xác hơn là ngõ 11 Thái Hà). Có vẻ đến hơi sớm thì phải (lúc đó tầm 10 giờ 20&#8217;), đến mới thấy có 2 hoặc 3 anh gì đó (trừ những người bên eXo).</p>

<p><strong>Lúc sớm</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3208/3127289114_6c42ab2824.jpg?v=0" title="Lúc sớm" ></p>

<p>11 giờ là mọi người có vẻ đã đến đông đủ. Chỉ có khoảng hơn 20 người &ndash; con số khá khiêm tốn so với dự tính. Tớ cứ nghĩ là phải tầm 50 người cơ ;). Chỉ sợ đăng kí chậm không có chỗ, hóa ra tớ là người đăng kí thứ 3 trong danh sách :)</p>

<p><strong>Mọi người đến đông [chắc chưa đủ :D]</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3290/3127289274_56552c8884.jpg?v=0" title="Mọi người đến đông [chắc chưa đủ :D]" ></p>

<p>Ở đấy gặp bao nhiêu là người ở nhiều công ty khác nhau, trừ tớ, tớ hiện chưa làm cho công ty nào cả :), vẫn đang đi tìm, có vẻ nhiều công ty không có part-time job thì phải. Tớ không nhớ hết được tất cả mọi người, chỉ xin liệt kê một số công ty: eXo Platform (tất nhiên là có Jeremi Joslin, 3 người nữa mà tớ đã trao đổi khá nhiều với 2 anh ở eXo), Tinh Van Media (2 bạn sinh viên năm 3 của trường ĐH Công Nghệ Quốc Gia, mới đầu tớ gọi 2 cậu này = anh, sau thì đổi ngược lại khi biết tuổi nhau :))), Moore Corporation (<a href="http://nghenhac.info;">http://nghenhac.info;</a> <a href="http://anhso.net">http://anhso.net</a> &ndash; có 1 người), VinaLive (<a href="http://phununet.com">http://phununet.com</a> &ndash; mạng xã hội dành riêng cho phụ nữ; 3-4 người thì phải); 1 người bên Tầm Tay (<a href="http://tamtay.vn">http://tamtay.vn</a>). 2 người đến từ <a href="http://teevn.com.">http://teevn.com.</a> Àh, cả Jason nữa, cuối cùng thì cũng được biết mặt anh này :). Một anh Tây của <a href="http://newhanoian.xemzi.com.">http://newhanoian.xemzi.com.</a> Còn một số người khác nữa nhưng tớ không nhớ hết được.</p>

<p><strong>Đố biết tớ đâu? :)</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3196/3127290146_951883aa5b.jpg?v=0" title="Đố biết tớ đâu? :)" ></p>

<p>Jeremi có một bài thuyết trình khá rõ về OpenSocial, nhưng tớ nghĩ đây chỉ là giới thiệu cơ bản,
hầu như những gì Jeremi nói thì cũng đã tìm hiểu trước rồi. Nhưng lạ là một số người hình như đến
tham gia mà chưa biết gì về OpenSocial hay sao ý hoặc là rất mơ hồ về nó thì phải??? Tớ không biết
sao nữa. Tớ cứ nghĩ là đây thực sự là sự kiện rất thú vị để trao đổi kiến thức, thông tin và còn
hack nữa chứ :), nhưng mà một số người đến đây chỉ để xem hay sao ý, dường như không có ý tưởng để
viết một cái opensocial gadget thì phải, hoặc là không muốn chia sẻ???</p>

<p>Bài thuyết trình kéo dài khoảng một giờ đồng hồ. Mặc dù phần demo có một số vấn đề với newhanoian
gadget nhưng bài thuyết trình rất rõ ràng. Thực sự rất thích sự cởi mở và giọng nói tiếng Anh chậm,
rõ (Jeremi là người Pháp). Sẽ post một số ảnh ở đây khi Jeremi gửi ảnh cho tớ, vừa gửi email rồi.</p>

<p>Sau đấy là đến giờ ăn trưa!!! Không có pizza như trong agenda :), nhưng mà có bánh mì, thịt, rau,
hoa quả&hellip; ngon. Cảm ơn eXo, Jason, Google về bữa trưa :).</p>

<p><strong>Chuẩn bị cho bữa trưa [Đầy thức ăn nhưng mà không có cái ảnh nào như thế :)]</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3211/3126459089_a0703a11de.jpg?v=0" title="Chuẩn bị cho bữa trưa [Đầy thức ăn nhưng mà không có cái ảnh nào như thế :)]" ></p>

<p>Ăn trưa xong mọi người giới thiệu về mình: bạn là ai, bạn đang làm gì, ý tưởng của bạn..blah blah.
Mọi thứ bạn muốn nói và muốn chia sẻ.</p>

<p>Tiếp theo là đến lúc hack. Đầu tiên là học cách viết gadget bằng cách code theo một gadget mẫu:
place searching trên newhanoian. Khá hay, đơn giản nhưng tớ biết một số người có vẻ chưa hoàn thành
hoặc không thích lắm thì phải. Một số người nói là không sử dụng javascript, chính vì thế mà rất khó
để code cùng mọi người.</p>

<p><strong>Đến lúc hack :)</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3088/3127289804_a93ff9ee3a.jpg?v=0" title="Đến lúc hack :)" ></p>

<p>Sau khi code gadget mẫu, mọi người có phần chia sẻ ý tưởng và tìm người cùng code một gadget theo ý
tưởng đó. Lạ là có mỗi tớ lên chia sẻ ý tưởng của mình :(.</p>

<p>Có một câu hỏi khá lạ (lùng) và lặp đi lặp lại: &ndash; Làm sao để mạng xã hội của tôi có thể trở thành
một opensocial container? Cách config thế nào? Thực sự đây là một câu hỏi lớn. Để có thể trở thành
một opensocial container, mạng xã hội đó phải đáp ứng một số chuẩn của mạng xã hội, phải implement
hệ thống opensocial api và còn nhiều thứ khác nữa. Thực sự theo tớ nghĩ rất khó để &ldquo;cái-gọi-là&rdquo;
mạng xã hội ở Việt Nam có thể implement mọi thứ để trở thành một container cho các opensocial app
khi những người quản lý của các mạng này hỏi những câu hỏi như thế? Nếu có thời gian tìm hiểu chắc
sẽ không hỏi câu này đâu :)).</p>

<p>Cũng hơi buồn tí khi mà thời gian kết thúc khá sớm, khoảng 4h chiều &ndash; sớm hơn 2 giờ so với dự kiến.
Đây cũng là điều dễ hiểu thôi vì dường như một số người muốn code nhưng một số người thì không hoặc
là chưa sẵn sàng.</p>

<p>Một chi tiết khá thú vị. Thông thường những sự kiện như này thì mọi người sẽ được phát một chiếc
T-shirt đặc trưng, nhưng lần này mỗi người được 2 cái cơ ;)). Theo tớ để ý thì có khá nhiều T-shirt,
thừa hơi bị nhiều so với dự tính. Không có cảnh xô đẩy (thì phải) như D3vF3st ở t.p Hồ Chí Minh.
Mỗi người một chiếc màu đen truyền thống, một chiếc màu trắng của bên <a href="http://teevn.com.">http://teevn.com.</a> Nhưng rất
không may là tớ nhận được 2 chiếc đều cỡ L. Tìm mãi mà chả thấy cỡ M đâu cả. Giá mà mình to hơn 1 tí
thì tốt, đỡ phải kén chọn ;))&hellip;</p>

<p>Thực sự cảm ơn Jeremi vì cái bắt tay ;), vì sự cởi mở. Cảm on mọi người đã đến. Tớ thực sự thích
OpenSocial Hackathon Hanoi :)</p>

<p>Xem thêm ảnh: <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/jeremi/sets/72157611434836951/">http://flickr.com/photos/jeremi/sets/72157611434836951/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSocial Hackathon in Hanoi]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/13/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-13T23:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/12/13/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is one of the most active day of mine :). With the opensocial hackathon in Hanoi, I have
chance to meet some interesting people.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My morning started in 9 A.M (OMG!!! But it&rsquo;s my normal day; I don&rsquo;t know why but I&rsquo;d really like to
work at late night. Yesterday, I stopped working at about 4 A.M. It&rsquo;s hard to define my work :).
Just do everything with computer: blogging, building some requested websites from customers,
experimenting new technology trend, improve programming skill, oh many more. Just my habit :).</p>

<p>It took me about half an hour to get to eXo Platform office. Coming a bit early (about 10h 20&#8217;),
I just saw 2 or 3 geeks sitting there.</p>

<p><strong>Early time</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3208/3127289114_6c42ab2824.jpg?v=0" title="Early time" ></p>

<p>11h everyone came. It&rsquo;s just about more than 20 geeks &ndash; this number is less than my expectation ;). I thought there must have been about 50 geeks ;).</p>

<p><strong>Everyone came</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3290/3127289274_56552c8884.jpg?v=0" title="Everyone came" ></p>

<p>I met many geeks from many companies, except me, I&rsquo;m currently not working for any company :), just finding! I don&rsquo;t remember all, but just list some here: eXo Platform (of course, Jereme Joslin, 3 other guys and I have much talk with two of them), Tinh Van Media (<a href="http://xalo.vn;">http://xalo.vn;</a> two 3th-year students from College of Technology), Moore Corporation (<a href="http://nghenhac.info,">http://nghenhac.info,</a> <a href="http://anhso.net">http://anhso.net</a>), VinaLive (<a href="http://phununet.com;">http://phununet.com;</a> 3-4 guys), <a href="http://tamtay.vn">http://tamtay.vn</a> (one guy), guys from <a href="http://teevn.com.">http://teevn.com.</a> Ah, Jason &ndash; now I know him ;), and a guy from <a href="http://newhanoian.xemzi.com/.">http://newhanoian.xemzi.com/.</a> There are more guys but currently I can not remember all.</p>

<p><strong>Where am I? :)</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3196/3127290146_951883aa5b.jpg?v=0" title="Where am I? :)" ></p>

<p>Jeremi had a very clear presentation about OpenSocial, but I think it&rsquo;s just introduction, everything he said I have known before. How strange it is when some guys coming here have no idea from OpenSocial??? I don&rsquo;t know why. I thought this event is really interesting to exchange idea and information, and to hack but some guys don&rsquo;t have any idea to code an opensocial gadget :(.</p>

<p>Jemeri&rsquo;s presentation took about 1 hour, although there is some technical problems with newhanoian gadget, but it&rsquo;s clear and I really like his openness and clear voice. He took some pics and I will post them here when having it.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s time for lunch!!! No pizza as proposed in agenda :). But it&rsquo;s really good with bread, meat, vegetables, juices&hellip; Thank for your lunch, eXo, Jason, Google :).</p>

<p><strong>Preparing for lunch [full of food but no such pic captured]</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3211/3126459089_a0703a11de.jpg?v=0" title="Preparing for lunch [full of food but no such pic captured]" ></p>

<p>After lunch we have some introduction: who you are, what you are working, your ideas..blah blah. Just everything you would like to talk, to share.</p>

<p>Coming back to hacking time. Just learn to code following a gadget example: place searching. It&rsquo;s fun, but I knew some guys did not complete or like it. Some guys said they have no idea about javascript so it&rsquo;s really hard for them to follow.</p>

<p><strong>Hacking time</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3088/3127289804_a93ff9ee3a.jpg?v=0" title="Hacking time" ></p>

<p>After the gadget example, we have an idea sharing section to talk with people about your idea of an gadget (social app). How strange to me when just me sharing it :(. What about others&#8217;???</p>

<p>A strange and repetitive question: &ndash; How to config my server to host opensocial app??? It&rsquo;s a really big question to answer. You have to meet some social standards, implementing opensocial api, any may other things. Currently, I think it&rsquo;s really hard for so-called Vietnamese social network to implement OpenSocial api.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a little sad to me when it ended too early, about 4 P.M &ndash; 2 hours earlier than expected. Why? Because it seems that some guys would like to code, some guys don&rsquo;t, perhaps they didn&rsquo;t have any idea to code an gadget??</p>

<p>One interesting thing, as usually every developer will get a T-shirt. But here we can get 2 T-shirt. A black one from Google D3vF3st, a white one from <a href="http://teevn.com">http://teevn.com</a> :). So interesting!!! But unlucky me, I got 2 L-size ones. I could not find M-size one :(. If only I could be more bigger&hellip;</p>

<p>Thank you, Jeremi for your friendly hand-shake ;), your openness; thank you all guys for coming. I really like and love it :)</p>

<p>See more pics here from Jeremi: <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/jeremi/sets/72157611434836951/">http://flickr.com/photos/jeremi/sets/72157611434836951/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSocial Hackathon và BarCamp Hà Nội]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/25/opensocial-hackathon-va-barcamp-ha-noi/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-25T02:38:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/25/opensocial-hackathon-va-barcamp-ha-noi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tin dành cho các bạn ở Hà Nội. Như mọi người đã biết, Google DevFest HCMC &ndash; The First Ever Google
Hackathon Tour in Vietnam<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> (ngày 4/11/2008) và BarCamp Saigon<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> (November 5, 2008) đã được tổ
chức ở thành phố Hồ Chí Minh và nhiều bạn ở Hà Nội không tham gia được (tất nhiên trong đó có tớ :(,
dù gì thì những sự kiện như vậy không thể không tham gia).</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>OpenSocial Hackathon ở Hà Nội</h2>

<p>&ldquo;Sau khi tổ chức thành công Google Devfest<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> ở thành phố HCM hôm 4/11/2008 và rất nhiều bạn ở Hà
Nội đã không thể tham dự, chúng tôi dự định tổ chức một Hackathon nho nhỏ tập trung vào hệ thống API
của OpenSocial. Các kỹ sư phần mềm của eXo Platform<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> (cùng với đội ngũ Google Devfest khu vực Đông
Nam Á) sẽ tới trao đổi với mọi người, một số ứng dựng OpenSocial API ở các dịch vụ mạng xã hội Việt
Nam sẽ được demo. Một kỹ sư của Google khu vực Đông Nam Á sẽ tham gia. Ngày tổ chức dự kiến:
13/12/2008.&rdquo; (Nguồn Jason).</p>

<p>Lịch trình hôm 13/12/2008 tại OpenSocial Hackathon:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>10:30AM – 11:00AM : Đăng kí</p></li>
<li><p>11:00AM – 12:00PM : Bài thuyết trình về openSocial</p></li>
<li><p>12:00PM – 1:00PM : brainstorming + pizza</p></li>
<li><p>1:00PM – 5:00PM : Viết các ứng dụng openSocial</p></li>
<li><p>1:00PM – 2:00PM : Hướng dẫn viết gadget openSocial</p></li>
<li><p>5:00PM – 6:00PM : Thuyết trình tổng kết kết quả làm việc buổi chiều</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Xem thêm: <a href="http://blog.exoplatform.org/2008/11/24/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/">http://blog.exoplatform.org/2008/11/24/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/</a></p>

<p>Chỉ có 50 ghế dành cho ai đăng kí sớm nhất và được lựa chọn Đăng kí ngay.</p>

<h2>BarCamp Hà Nội đang được chuẩn bị</h2>

<p>Xem thêm <a href="http://wiki.barcamphanoi.org.">http://wiki.barcamphanoi.org.</a></p>

<p>Tuyệt vời!</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://jasonlog.supersized.org/archives/131-Google-DevFest-HCMC-The-First-Ever-Google-Hackathon-Tour-in-Vietnam.html<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>http://www.barcampsaigon.org/<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>http://code.google.com/events/apacdevfest/<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>http://www.exoplatform.com/portal/public/en/<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSocial Hackathon and BarCamp Hanoi]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/25/opensocial-hackathon-and-barcamp-hanoi/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-25T02:04:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/25/opensocial-hackathon-and-barcamp-hanoi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good news to Hanoi developers! As we know, Google DevFest HCMC &ndash; The First Ever Google Hackathon
Tour in Vietnam<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> (November 4, 2008) did succeed, BarCamp Saigon<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> (November 5, 2008) did succeed.
However, these two events was held in Ho Chi Minh city, many developers from Hanoi missed it.</p>

<p>Now you can join OpenSocial Hackathon and BarCamp Hanoi :).</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>OpenSocial Hackathon in Hanoi</h2>

<p>&ldquo;After the success of Google Devfest<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> in HCMC on November 4, 2008 and many talent developers in
Hanoi missed the Event, we plan to hold a mini Hackathon in Hanoi with focus on OpenSocial API.
Software engineers from eXo Platform<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> (going with Google Devfest team in Southeast Asia Tour) will
interact with Hanoi based devs and geeks, some demos of OpenSocial API apps on Vietnamese social
networking services should be showed. An engineer of Google Southeast Asia could join to assist the
participants. The planned date is December 13, 2008&rdquo; (from Jason).</p>

<p>Agenda on December 13, 2008:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>10:30AM – 11:00AM : Registration</p></li>
<li><p>11:00AM – 12:00PM : openSocial Presentation</p></li>
<li><p>12:00PM – 1:00PM : brainstorming + pizza</p></li>
<li><p>1:00PM – 5:00PM : Coding your openSocial applications</p></li>
<li><p>1:00PM – 2:00PM : guided walkthrough a first openSocial gadget</p></li>
<li><p>5:00PM – 6:00PM : presentation of what have been done in the afternoon.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>More info: <a href="http://blog.exoplatform.org/2008/11/24/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/">http://blog.exoplatform.org/2008/11/24/opensocial-hackathon-in-hanoi/</a></p>

<p>Only 50 seats are available. Just register now.</p>

<h2>BarCamp Hanoi is on the way of preparation</h2>

<p>Get information and just don&rsquo;t miss it from <a href="http://wiki.barcamphanoi.org.">http://wiki.barcamphanoi.org.</a></p>

<p>Really interesting and good news!</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>http://jasonlog.supersized.org/archives/131-Google-DevFest-HCMC-The-First-Ever-Google-Hackathon-Tour-in-Vietnam.html<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>http://www.barcampsaigon.org/<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>http://code.google.com/events/apacdevfest/<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>http://www.exoplatform.com/portal/public/en/<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where is my Google SearchWiki???]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/23/where-is-my-google-searchwiki/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-23T09:36:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/23/where-is-my-google-searchwiki</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Where is the Google SearchWiki that is a new feature encouraging people to have search more with new
experience? Just 2 days after Google&rsquo;s announcement it&rsquo;s gone. Does it mean that SearchWiki is not
very helpful and Google decided to take it out?</p>

<p>Google says that this is a bug and is working on restoring SearchWiki now: “We’re really sorry that
people can’t use SearchWiki at the moment &ndash; we’re working to fix the problem as quickly as we can.
Please bear with us.”</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SearchWiki của Google đâu rồi???]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/23/searchwiki-cua-google-dau-roi/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-23T09:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/23/searchwiki-cua-google-dau-roi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tính năng xã hội mới có tính kích thích, tạo thêm trải nghiệm cho người dùng khi sử dụng bộ máy tìm
kiểm của Google đâu rồi? Chỉ sau hai ngày thì tính năng này không còn hoạt động nữa. Phải chăng
SearchWiki không thực sự hữu dụng và Google quyết định gỡ bỏ?</p>

<p>Theo Google lý do SearchWiki không hoạt động nữa là do SearchWiki có lỗi và họ đang cố gắng khắc
phục sự cố: &ldquo;Chúng tôi rất lấy làm tiếc khi người dùng hiện không thể sử dụng SearchWiki &ndash; chúng tôi
đang cố gắng hết sức khắc phục. Hãy thông cảm cho chúng tôi.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[http errors by images]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/22/http-errors-by-images/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-22T09:12:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/22/http-errors-by-images</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are many cases that HTTP errors occurs with tedious text like &ldquo;Access Denied&rdquo; or
&ldquo;Page Not Found&rdquo;. If we add an image for illustration, it&rsquo;s more interesting. Even people will like
to get HTTP errors to see such these interesting images :)).</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>400 &ndash; Bad Request</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/109/304192669_105139f8e0_m.jpg" width="400" title="- Bad Request" ></p>

<h2>401 &ndash; Unauthorized</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/122/304193001_7ed9b91756_m.jpg" width="401" title="- Unauthorized" ></p>

<h2>402 &ndash; Payment Required</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/106/304193323_3d98d9fcbe_m.jpg" width="402" title="- Payment Required" ></p>

<h2>403 &ndash; Forbidden</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/117/304193677_7ac63a179e_m.jpg" width="403" title="- Forbidden" ></p>

<h2>404 &ndash; Not Found</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/105/304194006_922af2210e_m.jpg" width="404" title="- Not Found" ></p>

<h2>405 &ndash; Method Not Allowed</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/112/304194299_2fc0718bb5_m.jpg" width="405" title="- Method Not Allowed" ></p>

<h2>406 &ndash; Not Acceptable</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/116/304194659_eca0264c29_m.jpg" width="406" title="- Not Acceptable" ></p>

<h2>408 &ndash; Request Timeout</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/120/304195027_092906cf44_m.jpg" width="408" title="- Request Timeout" ></p>

<h2>409 &ndash; Conflict</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/115/304195427_f15002a254_m.jpg" width="409" title="- Conflict" ></p>

<h2>410 &ndash; Gone</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/99/304195684_7ed943c933_m.jpg" width="410" title="- Gone" ></p>

<h2>411 &ndash; Length Required</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/109/304195993_bcc87426eb_m.jpg" width="411" title="- Length Required" ></p>

<h2>413 &ndash; Request Entity Too Large</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/101/304196358_0afd41ba2e_m.jpg" width="413" title="- Request Entity Too Large" ></p>

<h2>414 &ndash; Requested URL Too Long</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/113/304196775_0b461475f7_m.jpg" width="414" title="- Requested URL Too Long" ></p>

<h2>415 &ndash; Unsuported Media Type</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/120/304197126_079c77762b_m.jpg" width="415" title="- Unsupported Media Type" ></p>

<h2>416 &ndash; Requested Range Not Satisfied</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/111/304197454_7d2319e1d6_m.jpg" width="416" title="- Requested Range Not Satisfied" ></p>

<h2>417 &ndash; Expectation Failed</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/106/304197810_cbd6d2ff5e_m.jpg" width="417" title="- Expectation Failed" ></p>

<p>To me the most interesting one is: 411 Length Required :))</p>

<p>Recommended links:</p>

<p>List of HTTP status codes: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_HTTP_status_codes">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_HTTP_status_codes</a></p>

<p>Images for illustration: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/apelad/sets/72157594388426362/detail">http://www.flickr.com/photos/apelad/sets/72157594388426362/detail</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[xử lý một số lỗi HTTP bằng hình ảnh minh hoạ]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/22/xu-ly-mot-so-loi-http-bang-hinh-anh-minh-hoa/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-22T09:05:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/22/xu-ly-mot-so-loi-http-bang-hinh-anh-minh-hoa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Các trang xử lý lỗi HTTP thường ra một thông báo là đoạn text vô hồn kiểu như &ldquo;Access denied&rdquo; hoặc &ldquo;Page Not Found&rdquo;. Thử thêm một số hình ảnh minh hoạ này có lẽ sẽ tạo cảm giác vui nhộn hơn cho người dùng, có khi họ lại thích gặp những lỗi HTTP để xem những hình ảnh này :)).</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>400 &ndash; Bad Request</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/109/304192669_105139f8e0_m.jpg" width="400" title="- Bad Request" ></p>

<h2>401 &ndash; Unauthorized</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/122/304193001_7ed9b91756_m.jpg" width="401" title="- Unauthorized" ></p>

<h2>402 &ndash; Payment Required</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/106/304193323_3d98d9fcbe_m.jpg" width="402" title="- Payment Required" ></p>

<h2>403 &ndash; Forbidden</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/117/304193677_7ac63a179e_m.jpg" width="403" title="- Forbidden" ></p>

<h2>404 &ndash; Not Found</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/105/304194006_922af2210e_m.jpg" width="404" title="- Not Found" ></p>

<h2>405 &ndash; Method Not Allowed</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/112/304194299_2fc0718bb5_m.jpg" width="405" title="- Method Not Allowed" ></p>

<h2>406 &ndash; Not Acceptable</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/116/304194659_eca0264c29_m.jpg" width="406" title="- Not Acceptable" ></p>

<h2>408 &ndash; Request Timeout</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/120/304195027_092906cf44_m.jpg" width="408" title="- Request Timeout" ></p>

<h2>409 &ndash; Conflict</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/115/304195427_f15002a254_m.jpg" width="409" title="- Conflict" ></p>

<h2>410 &ndash; Gone</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/99/304195684_7ed943c933_m.jpg" width="410" title="- Gone" ></p>

<h2>411 &ndash; Length Required</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/109/304195993_bcc87426eb_m.jpg" width="411" title="- Length Required" ></p>

<h2>413 &ndash; Request Entity Too Large</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/101/304196358_0afd41ba2e_m.jpg" width="413" title="- Request Entity Too Large" ></p>

<h2>414 &ndash; Requested URL Too Long</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/113/304196775_0b461475f7_m.jpg" width="414" title="- Requested URL Too Long" ></p>

<h2>415 &ndash; Unsuported Media Type</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/120/304197126_079c77762b_m.jpg" width="415" title="- Unsupported Media Type" ></p>

<h2>416 &ndash; Requested Range Not Satisfied</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/111/304197454_7d2319e1d6_m.jpg" width="416" title="- Requested Range Not Satisfied" ></p>

<h2>417 &ndash; Expectation Failed</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20110124143736im_/http://farm1.static.flickr.com/106/304197810_cbd6d2ff5e_m.jpg" width="417" title="- Expectation Failed" ></p>

<p>Hay nhất là hình minh hoạ lỗi 411 Length Required =))</p>

<p>Xem thêm:</p>

<p>Danh sách mã lỗi <a href="HTTP:">HTTP:</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_HTTP_status_codes">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_HTTP_status_codes</a></p>

<p>Hình ảnh minh hoạ: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/apelad/sets/72157594388426362/detail">http://www.flickr.com/photos/apelad/sets/72157594388426362/detail</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yahoo! announed to make BrowserPlus open-source!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/20/yahoo-announed-to-make-browserplus-open-source/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-20T01:11:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/20/yahoo-announed-to-make-browserplus-open-source</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As Google did with Gears, on November 18, 2008 Yahoo! intended to make BrowserPlus open source.
BrowserPlus and Gears are aimed at improving browsers&#8217; native abilities so Web applications can
better match those running natively on a computer&rsquo;s operating system.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img class="center" src="http://l.yimg.com/a/i/us/bp/s/1.4/site/home-sprite.jpg" title="BrowserPlus" ></p>

<p>As on BrowserPlus&#8217; blog: &ldquo;The big idea here is that we&rsquo;ll have the whole platform open sourced by
mid-next year, and as soon as possible we&rsquo;ll have many of the services we&rsquo;ve written open sourced,
as well as the APIs needed to write new services. Our goal is to empower the community to contribute
actual patches and new services &ndash; code to compliment the feedback. As we move forward, we hope that
this platform will contribute to the open web by enabling rapid innovation and giving us all a
chance to weigh in on what exactly the web of tomorrow should look like.&rdquo;
(<a href="http://browserplus.yahoo.com">http://browserplus.yahoo.com</a>)</p>

<p>&ldquo;BrowserPlus is a technology designed to &lsquo;extend the Web,&rsquo; so that developers can build more
exciting Web applications and so end users can get more done inside their Web browsers,&rdquo; Yahoo
said on a BrowserPlus frequently-asked-questions page. (<a href="http://browserplus.yahoo.com/faq/">http://browserplus.yahoo.com/faq/</a>)</p>

<p>Technology is changing so fast, who knows what is the tomorrow browser look like? When combining
Google Gears and Yahoo! BrowserPlus will actully make browsers a &ldquo;web OS&rdquo;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yahoo! công bố phần mềm nguồn mở BrowserPlus]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/20/yahoo-cong-bo-phan-mem-nguon-mo-browserplus/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-20T00:59:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/20/yahoo-cong-bo-phan-mem-nguon-mo-browserplus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cũng giống như Google đã từng công bố nguồn mở đối với Gears thì ngày 18/11 vừa rồi Yahoo! chính
thức công bố BrowserPlus trở thành phần mềm nguồn mở. Cả Google Gears và BrowserPlus đều có chung
mục đích là tăng thêm tính năng cho trình duyệt để các ứng dụng web có thể chạy tốt hơn và thậm chí
có thể chạy trong môi trường hệ điều hành mà không cần đến trình duyệt.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img class="center" src="http://l.yimg.com/a/i/us/bp/s/1.4/site/home-sprite.jpg" title="BrowserPlus" ></p>

<p>Trên Blog của BrowserPlus có nói: &ldquo;Chúng tôi có ý tưởng đến giữa năm tới toàn bộ nền tảng sẽ là
nguồn mở khi chúng tôi có các dịch vụ mã nguồn mở cũng như hệ thống API cần thiết để viết các dịch
vụ mới. Mục tiêu của chúng tôi là cho phép cộng đồng đóng góp thêm các gói dịch vụ mới. Khi chúng
tôi tiếp tục phát triển, hy vọng nền tảng này sẽ đóng góp vào web mở và cho chúng tôi cơ hội đánh
giá web của tương lai sẽ như thế nào.&rdquo;
(<a href="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20120104122121/http://browserplus.yahoo.com/">http://wayback.archive.org/web/20120104122121/http://browserplus.yahoo.com/</a>)</p>

<p>&ldquo;BrowserPlus là một công nghệ được thiết kể để mở rộng web, từ đó các nhà phát triển có thể xây dựng
những ứng dụng web thú vị hơn và do đó người dùng cuối sẽ làm được nhiều việc hơn trong trình duyệt
của mình&rdquo; &ndash; Theo Yahoo! trong trang những câu hỏi thường gặp (<a href="http://browserplus.yahoo.com/faq/">http://browserplus.yahoo.com/faq/</a>)</p>

<p>Công nghệ thay đổi từng giờ, ai biết được rồi mai đây web sẽ như thế nào. Khi kết hợp công nghệ
Google Gears và Yahoo! BrowserPlus, trình duyệt thực sự sẽ trở thành hệ điều hành web trong tương
lai.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SE Asia OpenSocial Application Contest]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/16/se-asia-opensocial-application-contest/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-16T15:14:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/16/se-asia-opensocial-application-contest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This contest is only for 5 SE Asia countries: Singapore, Malaysia, the Phillipines, Thailand, and
Vietnam. All developers from these 5 countries can take part in. Entries are limited to three per
person.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The Open registration day is November 15, 2008 and the close registration day is January 10, 2009.</p>

<p>Each entry will be judged by a panel of experts who are employees of Exo Platform, Friendster,
Globant, Google Inc, and hi5. Entries will be evaluated on:</p>

<ul>
<li>Creativity and user appeal</li>
<li>Internationalization (Message Bundles)</li>
<li>Use of other Google APIs</li>
<li>Cross-platform operability</li>
<li>Use of App Engine for storing user data and hosting files</li>
</ul>


<p>What about prize? :D</p>

<p>The top five entrants with the highest overall scores in each participating country will be awarded
an Apple iPod Touch (valued at US$230). In addition, the entrant with the highest overall score in
each participating country will also be awarded a Nintendo Wii (valued at US$270).</p>

<ul>
<li>Oh, nearly 2 months left to find ideas and implement an application ;)</li>
</ul>


<p>Useful links:
&ndash; <a href="http://code.google.com">http://code.google.com</a> &ndash; developer network; find opensocial section</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://code.google.com/appengine/">http://code.google.com/appengine/</a> -App Engine Registration. What happens to Vietnamese developers?
We can&rsquo;t registry because of the verification step: &ldquo;Verify Your Account by SMS&rdquo;?</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://code.google.com/events/apacdevfest/contest/index.html">http://code.google.com/events/apacdevfest/contest/index.html</a> &ndash; contest site</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://groups.google.com/group/seasia-social-gadget-contest?hl=en">http://groups.google.com/group/seasia-social-gadget-contest?hl=en</a> &ndash; Questions and answers about
this contest</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[cuộc thi viết ứng dụng OpenSocial khu vực Đông Nam Á]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/15/cuoc-thi-viet-ung-dung-opensocial-khu-vuc-dong-nam-a/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-15T23:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/15/cuoc-thi-viet-ung-dung-opensocial-khu-vuc-dong-nam-a</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cuộc thi dành cho 5 nước thuộc khu vực Đông Nam Á (Singapore, Malaysia, Phillipines, Thái Lan và
Việt Nam). Tất cả những nhà phát triển thuộc 5 nước kể trên đều có quyền tham gia bằng cách viết tối
đa không qua 3 ứng dụng gửi đến cuộc thi để được thẩm định, đánh giá.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Cuộc thi bắt đầu từ 15/11/2008 đến 10/1/2009 là hết hạn nhận sản phẩm dự thi.</p>

<p>Các sản phẩm sẽ được đánh giá bởi hội đồng chuyên gia từ Exo Platform, Friendster, Globant, Google
và hi5 theo các tiêu chí:</p>

<ul>
<li>Sức sáng tạo và tính khuyến khích người dùng</li>
<li>Quốc tế hoá</li>
<li>Sử dụng các API khác của Google</li>
<li>Hoạt động đa nền (cross-platform operability)</li>
<li>Sử dụng App Engine để lưu trữ dữ liệu và chứa các files ứng dụng.</li>
</ul>


<p>Giải thưởng là gì? :D</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Mỗi nước được chọn 5 người có ứng dụng tốt nhất, mỗi người được nhận 1 Ipod trị giá US$230.
Trong số 5 người này chọn ra 1 người tốt nhất được nhận thêm 1 Nintendo Wii trị giá US$270.</p></li>
<li><p>Còn gần 2 tháng nữa, đang tìm ý tưởng viết 1 cái ứng dụng ;) để dự thi.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Link hữu ích:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://code.google.com">http://code.google.com</a> &ndash; developer network; chọn opensocial để tìm hiểu viết ứng dụng.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://code.google.com/appengine/">http://code.google.com/appengine/</a> &ndash; Đăng kí App Engine, nhưng đến phần &ldquo;Verify Your
Account by SMS&rdquo; tớ cố gắng kết hợp số phone tất cả các cách có thể nhưng vẫn bó tay :(. Chưa biết
đăng kí thế nào đây, cùng lắm thì host ở chỗ khác, thế là mất điểm ở tiêu chí sử dụng App Engine :(.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Cập nhật để Vefify:: Không verify được ở Việt Nam, bạn hãy điền vào form mẫu sau đây để được verify.
<a href="http://code.google.com/appengine/kb/sms.html#error">http://code.google.com/appengine/kb/sms.html#error</a></p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://code.google.com/events/apacdevfest/contest/index.html">http://code.google.com/events/apacdevfest/contest/index.html</a> &ndash; Trang web cuộc thi</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://groups.google.com/group/seasia-social-gadget-contest?hl=en">http://groups.google.com/group/seasia-social-gadget-contest?hl=en</a> &ndash; Hỏi đáp cuộc thi. Tớ hỏi mấy
câu mà chưa thấy ai trả lời :(</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Việt Nam đoạt giải nhất cuộc thi bảo mật uy tín nhất châu Á]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/08/viet-nam-doat-giai-nhat-cuoc-thi-bao-mat-uy-tin-nhat-chau-a/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-08T19:16:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/08/viet-nam-doat-giai-nhat-cuoc-thi-bao-mat-uy-tin-nhat-chau-a</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Với số điểm 5.800, đội Bluemoon đã chiến thắng tại cuộc tranh tài CtF trong khuôn khổ Hội nghị bảo
mật máy tính Hack In The Box (HITB) 2008, diễn ra cuối tháng 10 ở Kuala Lumpur (Malaysia).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Cuộc thi CtF (Capture the Flags – Cướp cờ) năm nay có 7 đội tham dự từ Hàn Quốc, Singapore và Việt
Nam. Ngoài Blue Moon, đội Mitdac cũng gồm những chuyên gia bảo mật hàng đầu của Việt Nam đã đoạt
giải nhì với gần 1.800 điểm.</p>

<p>Trong cuộc thi &ldquo;cướp cờ&rdquo;, các đội sẽ được cấp một máy chủ trên đó có các ứng dụng nền (daemon) chứa
lỗi bảo mật. Người tham gia phải khai thác lỗ hổng, xâm nhập các máy chủ khác và bảo vệ server của
mình trước những đợt tấn công.</p>

<p>Được biết đến như là DefCon của phương Đông, HITB CtF là sự kiện lớn nhất về an toàn thông tin trong
khu vực châu Á &ndash; Thái Bình Dương và Trung Đông, được tổ chức mỗi năm 2 lần. Hội nghị quy tụ nhiều
nhân vật nổi tiếng và được các hãng lớn như Oracle, Microsoft, Intel, F-Secure&hellip; tài trợ.</p>

<p>HITB 2008 tập trung thảo luận và trình diễn các phương pháp thâm nhập hệ thống bảo mật từ nhận dạng
sinh học, nhận dạng bằng sóng radio tầm ngắn (RFID) cho đến các công nghệ không dây hiện hành.</p>

<p>Nguồn: <a href="http://sohoa.vnexpress.net/tin-tuc/doi-song-so/bao-mat/viet-nam-doat-giai-nhat-cuoc-thi-bao-mat-uy-tin-nhat-chau-a-1534438.html">http://sohoa.vnexpress.net/tin-tuc/doi-song-so/bao-mat/viet-nam-doat-giai-nhat-cuoc-thi-bao-mat-uy-tin-nhat-chau-a-1534438.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vietnam got the first prize in an Asian Security Contest]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/08/vietnam-got-the-first-prize-in-an-asian-security-contest/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-08T12:52:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/08/vietnam-got-the-first-prize-in-an-asian-security-contest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With 5,800 points, Bluemoon team won at the CtF (Capture the Flags) contest in a security
conference – Hack In The Box (HITB) 2008 which took place at the end of November in Kuala Lumpur
(Malaysia).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>This year CtF contest had 7 teams from Korea, Singapore and Vietnam. Besides Bluemoon team, Mitdac
team consisting of top rank security experts in Vietnam got the second prize with nearly 1,800
points.</p>

<p>In the CtF contest, all the teams are provided a server having security holes in daemon. The
participants have to exploit these holes, break into other servers and defend their own server
against other attacks.</p>

<p>Known as the East Defcon, HITB CtF is a big event about security in Asia-Pacific and Middle East
taking place every two year. The conference assembles many famous experts and is sponsored by big
companies such as Oracle, Microsoft, Intel, F-Sercure.</p>

<p>HITB 2008 focused on discussion and demonstrated methods of breaking into security systems such as
biological identification, radio frequency identification and current wireless technology.</p>

<p>Source: <a href="http://sohoa.vnexpress.net/tin-tuc/doi-song-so/bao-mat/viet-nam-doat-giai-nhat-cuoc-thi-bao-mat-uy-tin-nhat-chau-a-1534438.html">http://sohoa.vnexpress.net/tin-tuc/doi-song-so/bao-mat/viet-nam-doat-giai-nhat-cuoc-thi-bao-mat-uy-tin-nhat-chau-a-1534438.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drupal giành giải CMS mã nguồn mở 2008]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/06/drupal-gianh-giai-cms-ma-nguon-mo-2008/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-06T22:48:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/06/drupal-gianh-giai-cms-ma-nguon-mo-2008</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hôm nay cuộc thi hệ quản trị nội dung (CMS) nguồn mở thường niên do nhà xuất bản Packt tổ chức đã lên đến đỉnh điểm khi Packt thông báo Drupal đã giành được giải Overall (Tổng thể) với giải thưởng trị giá 5.000 đô-la. Sau 3 tháng, Drupal nhận được 20.000 phiếu bình chọn và về đích trước Joomla! Và DotNetNuke để giữ nguyên danh hiệu đã giành được năm 2007.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Dự án mã nguồn mở này được nhà sáng lập – Dries Buytaert công bố vào năm 2001 và Drupal đã nhanh chóng lớn mạnh, được download khoảng 1,5 triệu lần trong vòng 12 tháng vừa qua. Hiện Drupal các công ty như Warner Brothers Music, MTV UK, trang tin New York Observer và nhiều công ty sử dụng.
Nhận được giải này Buytaert phát biểu &ldquo;Những phần thưởng này có được chính là nhờ những đóng góp rất lớn từ cộng đồng thành viên Drupal trên toàn thế giới&rdquo;. Buytaert kết luận: &ldquo;Cộng đồng Drupal đang nỗ lực làm việc để xây dựng tương lai cho web động để từ đó bất cứ ai cũng có thể xây dựng những website xuất bản nội dung lớn&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Với các lá phiếu từ các chuyên gia cùng khách ghé thăm website của nhà xuất bản Packt, các giải thưởng năm nay chứng tỏ sự phổ biến cũng như chất lượng cao của giải. Việc chọn ra top 3 hệ thống trong vòng chung kết thực sự là một nhiệm vụ khó khăn cho hội đồng đánh giá vì các hệ thống này đều đạt chuẩn cao và có vô số tính năng.</p>

<p>Đứng thứ hai và nhận được giải thưởng 3.000 đô-la là Joomla! – cái tên trẻ nhất (được thành lập năm 2003) trong top 3 hệ thống và trước đây cũng đã giành giải Overall. Hội đồng đánh giá rất có ấn tượng với cách cài đặt dễ dàng và khả năng tạo website hoạt động ngay chỉ trong thời gian rất ngắn của Joomla. Được cộng đồng đông đảo và đầy nhiệt huyết đóng góp xây dựng chính là yếu tố khiến dự án lớn mạnh nhanh chóng trong một khoảng thời gian ngắn đến như vậy.</p>

<p>Đứng ở vị trí thứ 3 và nhận được giải thưởng 2.000 đô-la là DotNetNuke &ndash; hệ thống CMS duy nhất được viết bằng VB.NET cho ASP.NET framework. DotNetNuke nhận được phải hồi tích cực từ hội đồng đánh giá khi họ rất ấn tượng với cách phát triển dễ dàng và các tính năng bảo mật.</p>

<p>Cùng với giải Overall, nhà xuất bản Packt cũng có các giải cho CMS nguồn mở PHP tốt nhất và CMS nguồn mở tốt nhất không viết bằng PHP. Và giải cuối cùng chính là CMS nguồn mở triển vọng dành cho SilverStripe. Packts trao tổng số tiền khoảng 20.000 đô-la cho các hệ quản trị nội dung đạt giải.</p>

<p>Giải thưởng khác gồm:
&ndash; Hứa hẹn nhất: SilverStripe
&ndash; PHP nguồn mở tốt nhất: Drupal
&ndash; CMS nguồn mở không viết bằng PHP tốt nhất: Plone.</p>

<p>Các giải thưởng này được đưa ra để phát hiện và trao giải cho các hệ thống CMS nguồn mở với những chuẩn nhất quán trong môi trường đầy tính cạnh tranh. Kết quả của giải thưởng năm nay nhấn mạnh đến chất lượng này và cũng nói rằng không nhất thiết một CMS nào phải là tốt nhất mà CMS đó tốt nhất khi phù hợp với nhu cầu và đòi hỏi của từng người dùng cụ thể.</p>

<p>Để xem toàn bộ kết quả của Giải CMS nguồn mở 2008, mời bạn theo đường dẫn sau: <a href="http://www.PacktPub.com/Award">http://www.PacktPub.com/Award</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drupal revealed as 2008 open source CMS award winner]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/06/drupal-revealed-as-2008-open-source-cms-award-winner/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-06T22:21:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/06/drupal-revealed-as-2008-open-source-cms-award-winner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Packt’s annual Open Source Content Management System (CMS) Award reached its climax today with the announcement that Drupal has won the Overall category, collecting a first prize of $5,000. Three months after it was launched and a staggering 20,000 votes later, Drupal finished ahead of Joomla! and DotNetNuke to retain the Award it won in 2007.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Released as an Open Source project by founder Dries Buytaert in 2001, Drupal has grown substantially and has been downloaded almost 1.5 million times in the last 12 months. It is currently being applied by companies such as Warner Brothers Music, MTV UK, and the New York Observer amongst others.</p>

<p>&ldquo;These awards are a testament to the valuable contributions from dedicated Drupal community members around the globe&rdquo; said Buytaert in response to the news. &ldquo;Working together, the Drupal community is building the future of the dynamic web so that anyone can quickly build great social publishing websites&rdquo; he concluded.</p>

<p>With votes coming from a panel of industry experts and visitors to Packt’s website, this year’s Awards proved to be the most popular and also the highest quality. The task of selecting a top three from the finalists was a difficult one for the judges due to their high standards and myriad features.</p>

<p>Finishing in second place and receiving $3,000 was Joomla!, the youngest of the three finalists and a previous winner of the Overall Award. Judges were impressed with Joomla’s ease of installation and ability to get a website up-and-running in a short space of time. Particular praise was reserved for its sizeable and enthusiastic community, which has allowed the project to grow so quickly in such a short space of time.</p>

<p>In third place and receiving $2,000 was DotNetNuke, the only CMS in the final that is written in VB.NET for the ASP.NET framework. DotNetNuke received positive feedback from judges who were impressed with its ease of development and security implementation features.</p>

<p>Alongside the Overall Award, Packt ran categories for best Open Source PHP Content Management System and best Open Source CMS that isn’t written in PHP. The final category was the Most Promising Open Source CMS, which was won by SilverStripe. Packt handed out a total of $20,000 in prize money to the winning Content Management Systems.</p>

<p>Winners in the other final categories include:</p>

<ul>
<li>Most Promising: <strong>SilverStripe</strong></li>
<li>Best Open Source PHP: <strong>Drupal</strong></li>
<li>Best non PHP Open Source CMS: <strong>Plone</strong></li>
</ul>


<p>The Awards were designed to recognize and reward Open Source CMS’s for their consistently high standards in what is an extremely competitive field. The result of this year’s Award confirms this quality and also suggests that there isn’t necessarily one CMS that is the best, more that there is the best one to fit an individual user’s needs and requirements.</p>

<p>Full results of the 2008 Open Source CMS Award can be found at <a href="http://www.PacktPub.com/Award">http://www.PacktPub.com/Award</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hoatle.net - giới thiệu]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/06/hoatle-net-gioi-thieu/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-06T22:04:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/06/hoatle-net-gioi-thieu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chào mừng bạn đến với weblog mới thành lập &ndash; hoatle.net! Trước tiên tôi có đôi lời muốn giới thiệu. Về tên miền weblog của tôi? Tại sao lại là hoatle.net; Đơn giản thôi, tên tôi là Lê Văn Hoạt, do vậy hoatle chính là sự kết hợp của tên (Hoạt) và họ (Lê). Hơn nữa, hoatle cũng là tên được tôi sử dụng nhiều nhất trên Internet, bạn thử google với từ khoá &ldquo;hoatle&rdquo; sẽ biết thêm 1 số thông tin về tôi. Sau vài tuần phát triển weblog này, đến thời điểm này thì hoatle.net có thể đi chập chững những bước đi đầu tiên để tôi chia sẻ cùng mọi người về nhiều khía cạnh trong công việc cũng như trong cuộc sống. Để giúp mọi người hiểu rõ hơn về hoatle.net, tôi xin nói về nguồn gốc, quá trình phát triển và làm thế nào để sử dụng tốt nhất weblog này?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Trước tiên, tôi muốn giới thiệu thêm về hoatle.net. Tôi thực sự rất thích viết về những vấn đề mình quan tâm, được tìm hiểu thông tin từ nhiều chiều và đưa ra quan điểm của mình. Blog đầu tiên tôi viết khá nhiều là Blog 360 của Yahoo! Bạn có thể ngó qua tại địa chỉ <a href="http://360.yahoo.com/wild_tiger8607.">http://360.yahoo.com/wild_tiger8607.</a> À, tôi xin nói luôn dần (tiger) chính là năm sinh của tôi, còn wild chính là để tôi mạnh mẽ hơn, không được hiền lành quá :P. Trong thời gian gần đây có quá nhiều sự việc không mong muốn đã xảy ra với tôi và cũng đã làm tôi thay đổi đôi chút. Tôi muốn làm việc nhiều hơn và thực tế tôi đã chơi ít đi và tận dụng bất cứ khi nào có thể để học và áp dụng những kinh nghiệm mới vào những dự án của mình. Trong quá trình học tập này, tôi có những kiến thức thú vị muốn được chia sẻ nhưng cách tổ chức Blog trên 360 của Yahoo! không thích hợp cho việc chia sẻ những kiến thức thiên về kỹ thuật này (hiển thị mã nguồn, định dạng hiển thị, cách tổ chức nội dung.v.v&hellip;). Do vậy tôi quyết định tự thiết kế cho mình weblog riêng để tôi có thể chia sẻ kiến thức được nhanh và hiệu quả nhất.</p>

<p>Tuy nhiên, quá trình thiết kế weblog này có khá nhiều sự thay đổi. Đầu tiên, tôi quyết định thiết từ đầu như tôi đã làm đối với website: <a href="http://dichthuatpti.com">http://dichthuatpti.com</a> (viết bằng ASP) và <a href="http://vinateximex.com.vn">http://vinateximex.com.vn</a> (viết bằng PHP). Bạn có thể thấy rõ 2 website được tôi thiết kế khá là đơn giản và có nhiều chỗ không hợp lý về cách tổ chức màu sắc, tuân theo các chuẩn thiết kế; cũng đơn giản thôi, hồi đó (cách đây 1 -2 năm) tôi mới làm để học chứ chưa phải học để làm. Tôi đã làm việc với ASP cách đây khoảng 2 năm sau khi tôi hoàn thành project kì thứ nhất ở Hà Nội &ndash; Aptech và sau đó là tự học PHP và thực hiện dự án cho công ty xuất nhập khẩu dệt may Việt Nam (vinateximex). Gần đây có thêm nhiều kinh nghiệm hơn về PHP và kiến trúc MVC (Model-View-Controller), tôi đã quyết định tự xây dựng cho mình một hệ thống MVC như thế bằng cách kết hợp một số công nghệ lại với nhau như Smarty &ndash; một &ldquo;template engine&rdquo; cho tầng &ldquo;Presentation&rdquo;, PEAR (bộ thư viện PHP) cho tầng &ldquo;Model&rdquo; và tôi tự viết tầng &ldquo;Controller&rdquo; từ đầu. Tất nhiên là tôi đã thất bại bởi vì thực sự hiện tại nó quá sức đối với tôi. Sau đó tôi tìm đến Zend Framework &ndash; một nền tảng được xây dựng lập trình PHP từ PHP 5.0 trở nên khi khả năng hướng đối tượng của PHP khá hoàn chỉnh và Zend Framework cũng theo kiến trúc MVC ngay từ đầu. Tôi đã mất khoảng một tháng để code và trải nghiệm với Zend Framework và cũng đã xây dựng được một website đơn giản với 2 thứ tiếng. Như bạn đã thấy, để đạt những yêu cầu ban đầu của weblog của mình, tôi phải làm việc nhiều hơn để lập kế hoạch, thiết kế cơ sở dữ liệu và nhiều vấn đề khác nữa. Tất nhiên là tôi đã thất bại bởi vì tôi có quá ít thời gian để hoàn thành nó. Vào thời điểm đó, tôi có một dự án bị &ldquo;delay&rdquo; khá lâu từ công ty dịch thuật PTI &ndash; xây dựng website với hệ thống đa ngữ. Do đó thay vì làm mọi thứ từ đầu, tôi quyết định mã nguồn mở sẽ là giải pháp của mình. Tôi có thể học rất nhanh một khi cái tôi cần học cho tôi nhiều cảm hứng. Tôi làm việc và học sử dụng một hệ quản trị nội dung mã nguồn mở. Tôi được biết đến Drupal cũng khá lâu từ dự án (không thành) với một người bạn và khoảng thời gian đó tôi cũng cảm thấy học Drupal khá khó. Do vậy tôi quyết định dành nhiều thời gian hơn cho Drupal và cũng đã hoàn thành xong giai đoạn đầu tiên cho dự án PTI &ndash; hiện tại mới có một loại ngôn ngữ (<a href="http://ptitranslation.com.vn">http://ptitranslation.com.vn</a>) và dự án D9 (cho lớp học đại học của tôi để chúng tôi có thể chia sẻ tài nguyên và làm cho việc học thú vị hơn, nhưng hiện nay cách quản lí nội dung khá không hợp lý và tôi đang tổ chức lại nội dung). Và sau đó sau một số tuần làm việc để quản lý cách chia sẻ kiến thức cũng như chia sẻ trong cuộc sống. Và đến thởi điểm này, hoatle.net thoả mãn yêu cầu của một weblog chia sẻ của tôi. Nó sẽ phát triển khi kinh nghiệm của tôi phát triển.</p>

<p>Vừa rồi tôi đã nói về quá trình hình thành và phát triển weblog hoatle.net. Còn các tính năng và cách chia sẻ thông tin của hoatle.net? Có một số tính năng nổi bật như: hệ thống menu: tôi đã làm việc khá nhiều để phân loại nội dung theo cách hợp lý nhất sau nhiều lần sửa đổi. Đến thời điểm này tôi khá hài lòng với hệ thống menu hiện tại: rất rõ ràng và gọn. Tính năng chia sẻ: đây là tính năng được tôi đặt trọng tâm ngay từ đầu, chia sẻ kiến thức, thực hành với một số dư án nhỏ cũng như chia sẻ thông tin về bản thân, cuộc sống. Sau một số dự án nhỏ tôi sẽ kết hợp tất cả lại vào một số dự án thực tế, khá là hay :D; Tính năng học tập: Bởi vì tôi chia sẻ ngay khi tôi được học một cái gì đó cần chia sẻ, do đó hãy học cùng tôi và nhất định mọi người sẽ cùng tiến bộ trong thế giới công nghệ thông tin, đặc biệt là khả năng lập trình; Tính năng hệ thống 2 ngôn ngữ: Tôi hiện đang học ở Bách Khoa Hà Nội &ndash; chuyên ngành tiếng Anh khoa học kỹ thuật và được đào tạo thành những biên &ndash; phiên dịch trong tương lai, do đó phát triển một website 2 ngôn ngữ như vậy sẽ giúp tôi luyện tập kỹ năng dịch nhiều hơn. Ngoài ra, tôi cũng mong muốn chia sẻ kiến thức cũng như hình ảnh Việt Nam cùng với bạn bè quốc tế. Tôi luôn tâm niệm: Học tập và làm việc để chia sẻ và chia sẻ để học tập và làm việc. Sẽ thế và luôn như thế :)</p>

<p>Cuối cùng nhưng không kém phần quan trọng là cách chia sẻ thông tin trên hoatle.net? Những người bạn của tôi có thể quan tâm đến đời sống cá nhân của tôi hơn là các yếu tố kỹ thuật, vì vậy mọi người có thể xem thông tin ở menu Blog nhá :D. Đối với những bạn lập trình viên thì cứ việc ngó qua tất cả những gì có trên weblog này. Tôi đảm bảo sẽ có nhiều điều thú vị khi đang chờ bạn khám phá ;). Đối với các khách hàng tiềm năng: giải pháp nguồn mở sẽ là giải pháp hiệu quả mà lại ít tốn kém nhất. Một khi kí hơp đồng, khách hàng sẽ nhận được tư vấn và hỗ trợ 24/7 và không hề có ngày hết hạn như hạn bảo hành gì gì đó. Hãy hợp tác và cùng phát triển. Còn riêng với bản thân tôi, viết weblog này sẽ cải thiện kỹ năng viết và văn hoá chia sẻ của mình.</p>

<p>Nói tóm lại, vừa rồi tôi đã giới thiệu về weblog mới hoatle.net: nguồn gốc, quá trình phát triển và làm thế nào để sử dụng tốt nhất weblog này. Bạn cứ tự nhiên khám phá và biết nhiều về công việc , các dự án, cũng như cuộc sống của tôi. Weblog này vừa mới đi vào hoạt động, tôi sẽ thường xuyên cập nhật nội dung khi các dự án và ý tưởng ngày càng nhiều hơn thì tôi càng muốn chia sẻ nhiều hơn. Nếu bạn có bất cứ thắc mắc nào cần giải đáp, hãy liên hệ với tôi qua biểu mẫu liên hệ. Cảm ơn bạn đã đọc những dòng này!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hoatle.net - introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/06/hoatle-net-introduction/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-06T22:02:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/06/hoatle-net-introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi everybody, welcome to my newly created weblog &ndash; hoatle.net! Let me introduce first :). Ah, about my domain name? It is very simple. My name is Hoat Le Van, so hoatle is the combination of my first (Hoat) and last name (Le). Moreover, hoatle is also my long-term username on the internet, just google to find out something about me, huh? After some weeks to develop this weblog, now it is open for me to share&hellip;uhm&hellip; so many things in life and in work :)! Some people want to know what is my weblog about and how to use it?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First of all, what is hoatle.net about? We should know a little history. I am really excited about writing many things that inspire me. My first weblog is from Y!&lsquo; 360 service. You can check it out from address: <a href="http://360.yahoo.com/wild_tiger8607.">http://360.yahoo.com/wild_tiger8607.</a> By the way, tiger is my year of birth as the convention of some Asian countries like China, Vietnam, etc. Recently, so many bad things happened to me, which has made me a bit different, I know it. I want to work more and in fact, I have played less and spent any time as I could with my computer to learn and to apply it in real life projects. In my learning curve, I found out some interesting knowledge to share, but my current blog on Y! is not suitable for me to share many different technical things in the easy way. And I decided to design my own weblog that meet my desire to easily share knowledge.</p>

<p>However, the development of designing this weblog got many changes in progress. Initially, I decided to make my own website designed from beginning as I did for some websites such as <a href="http://dichthuatpti.com;">http://dichthuatpti.com;</a> <a href="http://vinateximex.com.vn.">http://vinateximex.com.vn.</a> You could see that these two first website that I built for customers are somehow simple because these sites are only from my beginning into ASP and PHP programming. Working with ASP was about more than 2 years ago, and with PHP was nearly 2 years ago. After two years with some knowledge of PHP and recently with MVC, I decided to build my own MVC system from PHP by combining some technologies like Smarty for Presentation, PEAR for Model, and I write my own Controller. I failed, of course, because it was overwhelming to me. After that, I decided to build my own weblog on Zend Framework. I spent about a month to code and experimented with it and have made a simple bilingual website. As you could see, to meet my initial requirement I had to work much harder to write some planning, to design database schema, and a lot much more. I failed, of course, because I had short time to develop it. At that time, I had a project from PTI translation company for a multilingual website. So instead of reinventing everything, open source is my solution. I can work and learn to use a CMS (content management system). Have known Drupal for long but worked less and I thought it was exciting but difficult to learn. So I decided to work harder, I completed the first phase of PTI project (<a href="http://ptitranslation.com.vn">http://ptitranslation.com.vn</a>) (Currently, it has only one language) and D9 project (<a href="http://d9k50.net">http://d9k50.net</a>) (for my own university class to share learning resource, but currently it has poor management and I am going to reorganize it). And then after some weeks working on how to manage my sharing knowledge and sharing in life, now hoatle.net can work as my desire. It will evolve as my experience evolve and so do I.</p>

<p>You have known something about history and development. What about some features and how to use hoatle.net? Some outstanding features are: menu system: I have worked hard to categorize content on this weblog after many times of modifications. The menu system are really clear and neat, huh? Sharing: Ok, my weblog is for sharing interesting knowledge and practice it with some small projects. After some small projects, I will combine it into a real project, so awesome :D; Learning: Because I share immediately what I have learned, just learn with me to help us progress more in the world of computer, especially programming; Bilingual system: I am studying in Ha Noi university of Technology and expected to become a translator or an interpreter, so maintaining this bilingual system practices me more. Besides, sharing knowledge to many international visitors and developers is also my intention. With a simple mission in mind is that: Just learning and working to share and sharing to learn and work, I will try my best to achieve it.</p>

<p>Last but not least, how to use hoatle.net? To my friends: Check out blog menu to get my latest information. To developers: Move around any menu as you like, and check it out. I am sure there are many interesting things waiting for you ;). To customers: To get your belief in an open source solution, just give me your requirement about a web application and I will make it true with the least cost and in a really short time. You will get my 24/7 support when the contract is signed and support has no expire day. Is it so great to know that? To myself: improving writing skill and sharing culture.</p>

<p>To summary, I have introduced about my weblog hoatle.net: what is it about and how you can use it. So feel free to move around the website to know more about me and my work, my projects, my sharing, my support to many customers. This weblog is just beginning to operate, I will regularly update the content as my projects and ideas get bigger and bigger. If you have got any question, please contact me with the contact form. Thank you for your reading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
