<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: vietnam | blog.hoatle.info]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/tags/vietnam/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-03T07:15:03+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[hoatle]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vietnam got the first prize in an Asian Security Contest]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/08/vietnam-got-the-first-prize-in-an-asian-security-contest/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-08T12:52:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hoatle.info/2008/11/08/vietnam-got-the-first-prize-in-an-asian-security-contest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With 5,800 points, Bluemoon team won at the CtF (Capture the Flags) contest in a security
conference – Hack In The Box (HITB) 2008 which took place at the end of November in Kuala Lumpur
(Malaysia).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>This year CtF contest had 7 teams from Korea, Singapore and Vietnam. Besides Bluemoon team, Mitdac
team consisting of top rank security experts in Vietnam got the second prize with nearly 1,800
points.</p>

<p>In the CtF contest, all the teams are provided a server having security holes in daemon. The
participants have to exploit these holes, break into other servers and defend their own server
against other attacks.</p>

<p>Known as the East Defcon, HITB CtF is a big event about security in Asia-Pacific and Middle East
taking place every two year. The conference assembles many famous experts and is sponsored by big
companies such as Oracle, Microsoft, Intel, F-Sercure.</p>

<p>HITB 2008 focused on discussion and demonstrated methods of breaking into security systems such as
biological identification, radio frequency identification and current wireless technology.</p>

<p>Source: <a href="http://sohoa.vnexpress.net/tin-tuc/doi-song-so/bao-mat/viet-nam-doat-giai-nhat-cuoc-thi-bao-mat-uy-tin-nhat-chau-a-1534438.html">http://sohoa.vnexpress.net/tin-tuc/doi-song-so/bao-mat/viet-nam-doat-giai-nhat-cuoc-thi-bao-mat-uy-tin-nhat-chau-a-1534438.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
